From the silence
From the night
Comes a distant
Lullaby
Soul Surrendering your soul
(Subtitle Revised by HchC)
The heart in you not whole
For love
Walked out
Cast into the dark
Branded with a mark
Of shame
Of Cain
如果我能重回过去.
[Man Narrating]If I could just go back.
如果一切能够重来,
If I could rub everything out,
我会从我自己开始.
starting with myself.
从借一件外套开始
Starting with borrowing a jacket.
噢,稍纵即逝的天堂
Oh, such fleeting paradise
如此纯真的喜悦
Such innocent delight
为了去爱
To love
被爱
Be loved
摇篮曲轻唱
A lullaby
随即是一片死寂
Then silence
- 弗朗西斯，太动听了.    - 我很荣幸，谢谢.
- [ Woman ] Frances, that was lovely.   - I'm so glad. Thank you.
恭喜.
[ Man ]Congratulations.
太棒了.非常优美.
Marvelous.Most enjoyable.
赫伯特·格林立夫.这是我的妻子,埃米莉.
Herbert Greenleaf.My wife, Emily.
谢谢.汤姆·瑞普雷.
Thank you.Tom Ripley.
- 你好吗?  - 你以前在普林斯顿.
- How do you do ?  - You were at Princeton.
你很有可能认识我的儿子,迪克,迪克·格林立夫.
Most likely you'll know our son,Dick. Dickie Greenleaf.
我一眼就注意到了你的外套.
[Emily] I couldn't help noticing your jacket.
是的.
Yes.
56届的.
Class of'56.
迪克现在还好吗?
How is Dickie ?
很高兴与见你.
[Frances]We've enjoyed meeting you.
我希望你以后能常来看看我们.
I do hope that you'll come out and see us.
-谢谢.你们实在是太好了.  -二位都很好.
- Thank you. That's very kind.  - Both of you.
-赫伯特?  -是啊,是啊.我也很希望如此.
- Herbert ?  - Yes, yes. I very much hope so.
当然,迪克喜欢爵士.
Of course, Dickie's idea of music is jazz.
-噢,是吗.  -他有个萨克斯管.
- Oh, dear.  - He has a saxophone.
在我听来,爵士根本就是噪音.
To my ear,jazz is just noise.
不过是些靡靡之音.
Just an insolent noise.
-很高兴见到你.  -我也一样.
- Very nice to meet you.  - And you.
-先生.  -我们在船厂见.
- Sir.  - We'll see you at the shipyard.
-我也很期待.  -很好.
- I hope to. - Good.
我得赶快了!已经迟到了!
I have to run !I'm very late !
- 噢,你们简直太棒了!  - 你也很棒.
- Ah, you were great !  - You were great.
令人羡慕的一对,不是吗?
Darling couple,aren't they ?
是啊.出色的年轻人.
Yes, they are.Exceptional young man.
-非常感谢你的外衣.  -非常感谢替我出场.
- Thanks a lot for the jacket. - Thanks for filling in for me.
小心袖口.再见,弗朗.
Take care of that wrist.Bye, Fran.
相信我.现在买下I.B.M.股,在它崩盘之前.
Believe me.Buy I.B.M. now, before it splits.
你肯定能大赚一笔的.
You'll make yourself a fortune.
你真这么认为?
You think so ?
[ Chattering, indistinct ]
[Piano]
对不起.对不起.
Sorry.Sorry.
对不起.
Sorry.
你可能也听说过迪克一直在意大利.
[Mr. Greenleaf] You’ve probably heard Dickie's been living in Italy.
蒙吉.在那不勒斯南部.
Mongibello.South of Naples.
一个不知名的小地方.
No kind of place at all.
-早上好,先生. -弗兰克.
- Good morning, sir. - Frank.
玛吉,她的女朋友,
Marge,his young lady,
好像是在写什么书.
is supposedly writing some kind of book.
只有上帝知道他到底在干吗.
God only knows what he does.
据说他们成天呆在沙滩和游艇上.
By all accounts, they spend the whole time on the beach or in a sailboat.
那就是我儿子的才能..花钱如流水.
That's my son's talent..spending his allowance.
你能否考虑去趟意大利,汤姆?
Could you ever conceive of going to Italy, Tom ?
劝我儿子回来?
Persuade my son to come home ?
我会付你酬劳的...
I'd pay you...
1000美元.
a thousand dollars.
是这样,我一直希望能去欧洲看看,先生,但是...
Well, I have always wanted to go to Europe, sir, but...
很好.现在你有了去那里的理由.
Good. Now you can go for a reason.
[Man Vocalizing]
[Jazz ]
康特贝希.
Count Basie.
杜可艾林顿? 我听不出来.
Duke Ellington ?I don't know.
我听不出来.
I don't know.
迪兹-吉利斯帕.
Dizzy Gillespie.
我有趣的情人
My funny Valentine
我有趣的情人.
My funny Valentine.
- [Man, Woman Arguing.: Faint]
-我甜蜜有趣的情人
-Sweet, funny Valentine
我连这是个男人还是个女人都听不出来.
I don't even know if this is a man or a woman.
-[Continues]
- [Crashing]
[Arguing Continues]
查里帕克?
Charlie Parker ?
查里帕克.我知道，是《伯德》这张专辑.
Charlie Parker.I know it. It's Bird.
对了!
Yes !
-啊.
-[Ends]
- Ugh.
-来,我来拿.  - 谢谢.
- Here. I'll take it.  - Thanks.
1000美元唾手可得.
That thousand bucks should come in handy.
- 是啊,先生.  - 我来开.
- Yes, sir.  - I'll get that.
- 谢谢.  - 先生,你的旅途会很愉快的.
- Thank you.  - Sir. You're gonna have a great trip.
格林立夫先生和科纳德公司老板是老友.
Mr. Greenleaf is personal friends with the Cunard people.
[Opera.: German]
告诉你，格林立夫这个名字可是很管用的.
I can tell you, the Greenleaf name opens a lot of doors.
[ Horn Sounding ]
[Man Speaking Italian Over P.A. ]
-你会说英语吗?  -请问你的名字是?
- [Ripley] Do you speak English ?  - [Man] What you name, please ?
-瑞普雷.  -跟着我吧.没问题.
- Ripley.  - Follow me. No problem.
-这儿，瑞普雷先生.  -好的.
- Here, Signor Ripley.  - Okay.
嗯,那儿.那个.
Uh, there.That one.
-这个.  -请等一下,都齐了吗?点点看.
- This one.  - Wait, is that all ? Count them.
呆会见.就一个箱子,瑞普雷先生?
Attenzione.Just one suitcase, Signor Ripley ?
-是的.  -当心点.
- Si.  - Attenzione.
[ Man Speaking Italian ]
[ Italian ]
-你的秘诀是什么?  -什么?
- What's your secret ?  - Excuse me ?
不，我的意思是..你是个美国人,是吗?
No, it’s just that..You are American, aren't you ?
不,我是说--
No, it’s just that--
我有那么多行李,而你却,嗯,轻装上阵.
I have so much luggage,and you're so, um, streamlined.
这,你知道,我都有点不好意思了.
It's, you know,humiliating.
[ Italian ]
顺便自我介绍一下,我叫梅瑞迪斯.
I'm Meredith,by the way.
- 你好，我叫迪克.  - 梅瑞迪斯·兰德尔.
- Hello, I'm Dickie.  - Meredith Randall.
-嗯，迪克·格林立夫.  -你好.
- Um, Dickie Greenleaf.  - Hello.
你不是造船大亨格林立夫家的吧.
You're not the shipping Greenleafs.
哦,想不是来着.
Oh, trying not to be.
想跳船来着.
Trying to jump ship.
那么,嗯,他们刚刚把你的行李放错了地方吗?
So, uh, did they put your cases in the wrong pile ?
只不过,嗯，你刚才在"R"那一栏.
It’s just that, uh, you were in the "R" stand.
我好像看到你在那儿了.
I thought I saw you there.
我的父亲想让我回纽约.
My father wants me back in New York.
他造船.我宁可乘船.
He builds boats.I'd rather sail them.
所以我以我母亲的姓来登记.
So I travel under my mother's name.
-你母亲叫...  -埃米莉.
- Which is...  - Emily.
开个玩笑而已.
I'm just kidding.
你知道,很有趣的一件事,
You know,the funny thing is,
我也不是姓兰道尔.
I'm not Randall either.
我姓罗吉.
I'm Logue.
- 是...   - 是从事纺织业的罗吉.
- As in...  - As in the textile Logues.
想抛开这个行当.
Trying to shrug off the dress.
-我也是以我母亲的姓旅游的.  -兰道尔.
- I travel under my mother's name too.  - Randall.
是的.
Right.
- 那么,罗马,罗马,罗马.
- Oh.  - So, Rome, Rome, Rome. - Oh.
-我们看起来还挺配的.再见.  -再见.
- We're partners in disguise. Bye.  - Bye.
[ Shouting in Italian ]
[ Driver Singing in Italian ]
[ Chattering in Italian ]
[ Italian ]
[Bus Motor Starts]
- [Bus Drives Away]
- [Women Chattering]
[Ripley Speaking
Italian Slowly]
"未婚妻有张脸. "
“The fiancée has a face. “
[Resumes Speaking Italian]
[ Italian Continues ]
伯德.
Bird.
"这是我的脸. "
“This is my face. “
[ Italian ]
[People Chattering in Italian]
我猜你没还看过我新写的一章.
[Woman] So I guess you didn't look at my new chapter.
我会的,玛吉.我保证.
I will, Marge.I promise.
不过是太热了.
It’s just been too hot.
如果我今晚我为你做晚餐,你可以顺便看看.
If I make dinner at my place tonight,maybe you could look at it then.
迪克格林立夫?
Dickie Greenleaf?
-你是?  -汤姆,汤姆·瑞普雷.
- Who's that ?  - It's Tom. Tom Ripley.
汤姆瑞普雷?
Tom Ripley ?
-我们在普林斯顿是同学.   -是吗.
- We were at Princeton together.  - Okay.
我们认识?
Did we know each other ?
你好.呃,我认识你,所以...
Hello.Well, I knew you, so...
我猜你也该认识我.
I suppose you must have known me.
普林斯顿是一团雾.
Princeton's like a fog.
美国也是一团雾.
America's like a fog.
我叫玛吉·舍伍德.汤姆...对不起,贵姓?
This is Marge Sherwood.Tom...Sorry, what is it ?
-瑞普雷.  -你好吗?
- Ripley.  - How do you do ?
你好,玛吉?
How do you do, Marge ?
-你在蒙吉干吗?  -没什么.
- What are you doing in Mongi ?  - Nothing.
没什么事.
Nothing much.
不过是经过而已.
Just passing through.
-经过?  -是呀.
- Passing through ?  - Yeah.
你可真白.
You're so white.
你看见过这么白的男人吗,玛吉?
Did you ever see a guy so white, Marge ?
灰色,事实上是.
Gray, actually.
就像件内衣一样.
It’s just an undercoat.
-再说一遍?  -你知道,刚入门.
- Say again ?  - You know, a primer.
真有趣.
That's funny.
玛吉喜欢皮肤白的人，因为她自己就很白.
Margie likes that 'cause she's so white too.
是呀,我是很白，而你一点也不幽默.
Yes, I do,and you're not funny.
在你走之前请务必来和我们共进午餐.
You should come and have lunch with us before you go.
- 好吗,迪克?   - 当然,什么时候都可以.
- Yes, Dickie ?  - Sure, anytime.
很好,
Well,
真是巧啊.
coincidence.
我一点也不记得他.
I don't remember him.
真够搞笑的.
That's so funny.
希尔维那!嗨!
Silvana ! Hey !
我到处找你.
I've been looking all over for you.
你躲哪儿去了?
Where’ve you been hiding ?
今天你倒找我来了.剩下一星期都死哪儿去了?
Today you're looking for me. Where've you been the rest of the week ?
你总在工作. 来吧.上来.
You're always working.Come on. Get on.
和那个美国女孩在一起?
With the American girl ?
-抓紧我.   -我恨死你了.
- Hold on to me.  - I hate you.
-啊?   -我恨死你了!
- Huh ? - I hate you!
你是不是连我住哪里都忘了?
[Marge]Did you suddenly forget where I lived?
我知道了.我来晚了.我是一头猪.
I know. I'm late.I'm a swine.
-四点了.   -我刚起床.
- It's 4:00.  - I just woke up.
-哦.  -我很抱歉.对不起.
- Ohh.  - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 你才起床.   - 福斯托和我出去划船了.
- You just woke up.   - Fausto and I took the boat out.
我们去打鱼,天才刚亮,我们什么都没捕到.
We were fishing, and then it was dawn,and we caught absolutely nothing.
嗯,是吗,那好,我们没等你一起吃饭.
Mmm, yes, well,we ate everything without you.
- 我们?   - 是啊.
- We ?  - Yes.
-汤姆·瑞普雷来了.   -谁?
- Tom Ripley's here.   - Who ?
-汤姆.你好.   -你好.
- Tom. Hello.  - Hi.
-你好.    -你还好吧? 我们以为你失踪了呢.
-Hello.   -How are you? Thought you'd disappeared.
-我们都想派个搜索队去找你了.   -没有.
- We were gonna send out a search party.  - No.
-没有,还在这儿呢.   -汤姆在和我谈论他的旅途.
- No, still here.  - Tom was telling me about his journey.
我笑得鼻血都要喷出来了.
[Giggling] Made me laugh so hard I almost got a nosebleed.
- 那不是很爽?   - 闭嘴.
- Is that good ?  - Shut up.
我很抱歉.我很抱歉.
I'm sorry.I'm sorry.
我是很可耻.不过我爱你.
I'm despicable.But I love you.
-你爱我吗?你爱我吗?    -我煞风景了.
- Do you love me ? Do you love me ?  - I'm intruding.
你能替我调杯马提尼酒?
Can you mix a martini ?
- 当然.   - 我去吧.
- Sure.  - [ Sighs ] I'll do it.
- 哦.   -我调的马提尼酒很棒.
- Ohh.  - I make a fabulous martini.
[ Laughing ]
每个人都应该有一样才能.你的是什么?
Everybody should have one talent. What's yours ?
伪造签名,
Forging signatures,
撒谎,模仿别人.
telling lies, impersonating practically anybody.
超过三样了.没有人应该拥有一种以上的才能.
That's three. Nobody should have more than one talent.
好吧,来试试看.
Okay,do an impression.
- 现在?   - 是啊.
- Now ?  - Yeah.
我儿子唯一的一项才能就是...
[ As Mr. Greenleaf]The only talent my son has...
花钱如流水.
is for cashing his allowance.
- 什么?   -哦,我喜欢航行.
- What ?  - Oh, I like to sail.
相信我,我喜欢航行.
Believe me,I love to sail.
- 真的,我造船.   - 住嘴!
- Instead, I make boats.  - Stop !
- 其他人乘它们远航.   - 够了!
- Other people sail them.  - It's too much !
你让我浑身起鸡皮疙瘩.
You're making all the hairs on my neck stand up.
哦,是啊.爵士.哦.爵士.让我们看看.
Oh, yes. Jazz.Oh, jazz. Let's face it.
那不过是,那不过是--那不过是靡靡之音罢了.
It’s just, uh--It’s just insolent noise.
好像他真来了一样.
I feel like he's here.
-太可怕了,就像那个老混蛋真来了似的.   -太棒了.
- Horrible, like the old bastard's here.  - Good.
-太棒了.
That's brilliant.
-太棒了!你是怎么认识他的?
Brilliant !How do you know him ?
噢，我和他在纽约见过面.
Oh, I met him in New York.
玛吉!玛吉,真是太吓人了.
Marge !Marge, this is scary.
你得来听听.见过我父亲,
You've got to hear this.Meet my father,
赫伯特·理查德·格林立夫一世.
Herbert Richard Greenleaf 1.
很高兴见到你迪克的眼光不错.
Pleasure to meet you.Dickie's made a fine catch.
-真不可思议!   -我知道埃米莉一定也是这么想的.
- Uncanny !  - I know Emily thinks so.
-我弄不明白.   -太不可思议了.
- I don't get it.  - It's uncanny.
你能不能考虑去一趟意大利，汤姆,
Could you ever conceive of going to Italy, Tom,
然后,嗯,把他带回来?
and, uh, bringing him back ?
-什么?   -我会付给你酬劳.
- What ?  - I'd pay you.
如果你愿意去意大利,
If you would go to Italy,
劝我儿子回家来，我会付给你1000美金.
persuade my son to come home,I'd pay you a thousand dollars.
我绝不会回去.
[Dickie]I'm never going back.
还雇人大老远地跑这儿来...
To actually hire somebody to come all the way here...
把我拉回去...
to drag me back home...
肯定是神经有点毛病了，是不是?
Got to be a little insane, doesn't he ?
- 你好,福斯托.
- Ciao, Fausto.- [ Italian ]
-这位是汤姆.   -你好,汤姆.
- This is Tom.  - Ciao, Tom.
[ Italian ]
-我绝不会回去的.   -不过,我想...
- I'm never going back.  - No, I think...
你母亲,她的病,我觉得那样有点...
Your mother, her illness,I think that's...
这和我妈妈一点关系都没有.
It's got nothing to do with my mother.
她有白血病...这更让我厌烦他.
She's had leukem...This is what makes me boil about him.
是他想让我回去.是他想让我回去.
He wants me back.He wants me back.
-这和我母亲一点关系都没有   -你看，我不明白...
- It's got nothing to do with my mother.  - Look, I don't know...
回去.回纽约去.
Go back.Go back to New York.
要么就给他打个电话,如果你能找得到可用的电话,
Or call him, if you can find a telephone that works,
告诉他就是野马也不能把我拉回他跟他那个船坞那儿去.
and tell him wild horses wouldn't drag me back to him or his shipyard.
-嗨，汤姆.   -嗨.
- Hi, Tom.  - Hi.
玛吉，汤姆来告别.
Marge, Tom's saying good-bye.
噢，我来了.
Oh, I'll come down.
那么,嗯,你和我爸爸说过了吗?
So, uh, did you speak to my father ?
哦,你是对的...关于电话.
Oh, you were right...about the telephones.
- 我告诉过你.   - 根本连电话线都没有.
- I told you.  - There are no lines.
- 没问题.  - 这就是意大利.
- There's some problem. - That's Italy.
汤姆.你要走了?你有什么打算?
Tom. You're off ?What are your plans ?
哦，回去,我想,越慢越好.噢!
Oh, back, I suppose,as slow as I can. Oh !
这个破包!
This bag !
嗨.你喜欢爵士.
Hey.You like jazz.
我爱爵士.
I love jazz.
这是最好的.
This is the best.
贝克尔,罗林斯.
Baker, Rollins.
玛吉说她喜欢爵士,但是她以为格兰-米勒叫爵士.
Marge says she likes jazz,but she thinks Glenn Miller’s jazz.
-我可从没那么说过!   -《伯德》.
- I never said that ! - [Tom] Bird.
这才是爵士.
That’s jazz.
《伯德》? 问问我我的游艇叫什么名字.
Bird ? Ask me the name of my sailboat.
我不知道.你的游艇叫什么?
I don't know. What's the name of your sailboat ?
看啊!看啊!伯德!
Look ! Look !Bird !
这太荒谬了.船是女性化的.
[Marge]Which is ridiculous. Boats are female.
谁都知道你不能给一只船取个男人的名字.
Everyone knows you can't call a boat after a man.
- 他不是男人，他是上帝.   -好,我们一起去那不勒斯.
- He's not a man. He's a god. - Okay, we're going to Naples.
那儿有个俱乐部...也不算是个俱乐部,是个地下室.
There's a club...It's not a club, it's a cellar.
-很烂.   -是的,很烂.你不一定要来.
-It's vile.  -Yes, it's vile. You don't have to come.
太棒了. 太..太棒了.你会喜欢它的.
It's great. It's..It's great.You're gonna love it.
你好吗?
How are you ?
-[Ends]
- [People Applauding]
哦!
Oh !
[ Italian ]
那太棒了.把他带上来.
That'd be cool.Bring him up.
[ Italian ]
汤姆·瑞普雷!
Tom Ripley !
来呀!快上来!
Come on !Get on up here !
-吔!
- Yeah !-  [ Italian ]
我会告诉你从什么时候开始唱的.
I'll tell you when to join the chorus.
来吧.
Come on.
好.一起来!
Okay.Together !
[ Italian ]
我遇到了一个普林斯顿的同学,
[Dickie] I bumped into an old friend from Princeton,
-一个叫汤姆·瑞普雷德家伙.
- a fellow called Tom Ripley.- [Keyboard Clacking]
他说他会一直缠着我直到我同意...
He says he's going to haunt me until I agree...
和他一起...
to go back to New York...
回纽约.
with him.
下午好.
Afternoon.
几点了?
What time is it ?
-噢, 天.  - "和他一起回纽约."
- Oh, God. - "Go back to New York with him."
- 这儿...   - 你总是打印信件?
- Here... - You always type your letters ?
-这儿应该是两个"T".   -我不会写,我也不会拼.
- That should be two T's. - I can't write, and I can't spell.
这就是一流教育赋予的特权.
It's the privilege of a first-class education.
你的房间在后面楼上.
Your room's upstairs at the back.
我想厄玛琳达已经整理好了床铺，厄玛琳达!
I think Ermalinda made up the bed. Ermalinda !
[ Both Speaking Italian ]
-你真是太好了.   -别再提了.
- This is so good of you. - Don't say it again.
现在你是个双面间谍了，我们一起合谋来骗我父亲,
Now that you're a double agent and we're going to string my dad along,
你说我们用你的佣金买辆车怎么样?
what if we were to buy a car with your expense money ?
- 好啊.    - 太好了.
- Okay.   - Great.
-你好,汤姆.   -你好.
- Hello, Tom.  - Hello.
玛吉,玛吉,你说怎么样?
Marge, Marge,what do you think ?
用我爸爸的钱买辆小车?
Little Ciquencento with my dad's money ?
哦，拜托，迪克.你连车都不会开.
Oh, please, Dickie.You can't even drive a car.
-你连车都不会开.   -我们现在需要的是个冰箱.
- [Tom] You can't even drive. - What we need urgently is an icebox.
你怎么认为?同意我吧,我保证我们会成为终生的朋友.
What do you think ? Agree with me,and I'll be your friend for life.
-我完全同意玛吉.  -嗯.
- I absolutely agree with Marge. - Hmm.
冰箱.冰箱.
Icebox. Icebox.
[Bell Tolling]
那么,什么,他会搬来和你一起住?
[Marge]So, what, is he gonna move in with you ?
就一段时间.他能--他能让我发笑.
It'll just be for a little while.He can be-- He makes me laugh.
-好吧,亲爱的.    -保证?
- Okay, darling. - Promise you'd say ?
-不,我喜欢他.   -玛吉,你谁都喜欢.
- No, I like him. - Marge, you like everybody.
不喜欢你.
[Chuckles]Don't like you.
那我会搬去你那儿，你和汤姆一起住好了.
Then I'll go to your place and you can move in with Tom.
我喜欢他.
[ Imitating Marge ]I like him.
玛吉,你谁都喜欢.
[ Imitating Dickie ]Marge, you like everybody.
-不,我喜欢他.
[ Imitating Marge ]No, I like him.
玛吉,你谁都喜欢.
[ Imitating Dickie ]Marge, you like everybody.
现在你知道为什么舍伍德小姐总是会在早餐时出现.
[Dickie] Now you'll find out why Miss Sherwood always shows up for breakfast.
不是爱.是我的咖啡机.
It's not love.It's my coffee machine.
自从厄玛琳达教他怎样自己煮咖啡,
[Marge] Ever since Ermalinda showed him how to make his own espresso,
他就觉得自己是成人了.
he feels like quite the grownup.
-是我买的咖啡机.   -噢,亲爱的,那杯是给我的?
-I bought the coffee machine.  -[Marge] Oh, darling, is that for me ?
这杯是给汤姆的, 因为他不会抱怨.
This is for Tom, because he didn't complain.
那戒指太美了.
[Tom] That ring is superb.
噢,汤姆,我爱你.知道了吧?
Oh, Tom, I love you.See ?
唔!我还得很郑重地发誓,决不取下它.
Ooh ! I had to promise,capital "P," never to take it off.
-要不然,我会把它送给你.  -是不是很棒? 我在那不勒斯淘到的.
-Otherwise, I'd give it to you. -Isn't it great ? I found it in Naples.
我为了买下它整整还了两周的价.
I had to bargain for it for about two weeks.
我希望它不便宜,玛吉.
I hope it wasn't cheap,Marge.
-哦,是很便宜.
- Oh, it was. - [ Chuckles ]
我得为弗朗西斯买件生日礼物，也许你能帮帮我.
I have to get a birthday present for Frances, so perhaps you could help me.
-谁是弗朗西斯?   -我的未婚妻.
- Who's Frances ? - My fiancée.
订婚了?你可真是出其不意啊,瑞普雷.
Engaged ?You're a dark horse, Ripley.
-她是谁?    -你的父母见过她.
- Who is she ?  - Your parents met her.
哦,天啊.噢,我能想象.
Oh, God.Oh, I can just imagine.
"如果迪克能成家该多好.
"If only Dickie would settle down.
每一对父母都该有个孙子不是吗?"
Doesn't every parent deserve a grandchild ?"
哦,天.决不.决不.
Oh, God.Never. Never.
我以你的戒指发誓，玛吉，我永远也不回去.
I swear on your ring, Marge,I'm never going back.
-告诉我什么时候该拉.  -现在拉.拉.
- [ Tom ] Say when to pull. - [ Dickie ] Pull now. Pull.
那不是在拉.我做错了.
It's not pulling.I'm doing it wrong.
-现在好点了,嗯?  -好,好,好.
- Better now, huh ? - Okay, okay, okay.
就由你来开船了.
We'll make a sailor of you yet.
你做得很不错.
You're doing really well.
-好了.酒吧时间.   -好,请.
- All right. Bar's open.  - Yes, please.
- 嗨,我们能开船去威尼斯吗?   - 好啊.我爱威尼斯.
- Hey, can we sail to Venice ?  - Sure. I love Venice.
"看到威尼斯死而无憾."是吗? 要么应该是罗马?
"See Venice and die."Isn't that right ? Or is it Rome ?
-是罗马吗?   -我得说是威尼斯.
- Is it Rome ?  - I have to see Venice.
你做了一些事情后便死而无憾了,不是吗?威尼斯就是其中之一
You do something and die, don't you ?Okay. Venice is on the list.
还有罗马.
And Rome.
你会滑雪吗?
Do you ski ?
啊,不是吧,不是吧.别说真是这样.
Ah, no, no.Don't tell me.
你完了.这是接下来要做的一件事.
You're a lost cause.That's the next thing to deal with.
圣诞节,我们打算去科尔蒂纳滑雪.
Christmas, we’re planning a skiing trip to Cortina.
-很棒的滑雪.太棒了.玛吉.   -什么?
- Excellent skiing. Excellent. Marge.  - Yes ?
不可思议.汤姆连滑雪都不会.
Unbelievable.Tom can't ski either.
-我们还得再教他滑雪.   -谢谢.
- We'll have to teach him that too.  - Thank you.
太掉价了,玛吉.这家伙有没有什么会的?
Such low class, Marge.Does this guy know anything ?
我们还没快结婚真是幸事.
Good thing we're not getting married soon.
否则我们还得请汤姆和我们共度蜜月.
We'd have to invite Tom on our honeymoon.
哦,我恨纽约.恨拥挤的帕克大道.
[Marge] Oh, I hated New York.That whole Park Avenue crowd.
所以我飞去巴黎打算专心写我的书.
So I fled to Paris to work on my book.
我经常会去蒙特利尔的一家咖啡馆...
And I was always going to this cafe in Monmartre...
和让-让克一起.
with Jean-Jaques.
迪克会演奏《我有趣的情人》
And Dickie would play "My Funny Valentine."
只是我后来才发现原来他就会那六首曲子.
It was only later that I found out he only knows about six songs.
不过,我很想见见他,我想.
Anyway, I looked forward to seeing him, I suppose.
[ Speaking Italian ]
[Men Chattering in Italian]
嗨,嗨,格林立夫先生!
Hey, hey, Signor Greenleaf !
你七点还没到我那儿,汤姆和我打算私奔了.
You're not at my place by 7.:00,Tom and I are running off together.
-好啊，很好.   -噢，迪克!
- Okay, fine.  - [Man] Oh, Dickie !
[ Indistinct ]
哦,等会儿.等会儿.
Oh, hold on.Hold on.
希尔维那,希尔维那
Silvana, Silvana
你让我微笑
You make me smile
我得和你谈谈.
I need to talk to you.
[Continues]
-你快把我的肋骨压断了!   -什么?
- [ Dickie ] You're breaking my ribs !  - What ?
你快把我的肋骨压断了!
You're breaking my ribs !
但是请不要
But don't
为我改变一丝一毫
Change a hair for me
如果你
Not if you care
真爱我
For me
留下,小瓦伦丁
Stay, little Valentine
留下
Stay
每一天
Each day
都是情人节
Is Valentine's Day
噢!
Ohh ![ Kisses ]
我都能干这只冰箱了,我太爱它了.
I could fuck this icebox,I love it so much.
那么，你在纽约是做什么的?
So, what did you actually do in New York ?
四处弹钢琴.我告诉过你.
Played piano in a few places.I told you.
好,那只是一份工作.你说过你有好几份工作.
Well, that's one job.You told me a lot of jobs.
好几个地方.那就是好几份工作了.
Few places.That's a few jobs.
神秘的瑞普雷先生.
The mysterious Mr. Ripley.
玛吉和我花了好些时间推测.
Marge and I spend hours speculating.
无论如何,我连想都不愿想到纽约.
Anyway, I don't even want to think about New York.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready ?
- 冰啤酒.谢谢,老爸.    - 好.
- Cold beer. Thank you, Dad.  - Okay.
从这儿开始抄.
Copy out from here.
- 你把这个一起带到欧洲来了?     - 你打算写吗?
- You bring this with you to Europe ? - You gonna write something ?
我注意到你带来了莎士比亚却没带来衣服.
I love the fact that you brought Shakespeare with you but no clothes.
厄玛琳达告诉我你每天晚上都洗同一件衬衫，是吗?
Ermalinda says you wash out the same shirt every night. Is that true ?
没有.我的衬衫不止一件.
No. I have more than one shirt.
她会帮你洗的.
She can do that for you.
不过,你也可以穿我的衣服.
Anyway, just wear some of my stuff.
随便穿.大多都有些旧了.
Wear anything you want. Most of it's ancient.
现在签个名.
Now your signature.
不是这样迪克.你的签名.
Not Dickie.Your signature.
不带眼镜,你还挺帅的.
Without the glasses,you're not even ugly.
我不需要眼镜，因为我从来不看书
I don't need them because I never read.
-我看起来怎么样?   -像克拉克-肯特.
- How do I look ?  - Like Clark Kent.
-现在是超人了.   -超人.
- Now Superman.  - Superman.
-好.    -我知道了.
- Okay.  - I know.
这像个小孩子写的.看见没有, 这个 "S"和"T"?看起来很脆弱.
It's like a kid's. See this, the "S" and the "T" ? Fine, vulnerable.
那是痛苦.那是不为人知的痛苦.
That's pain.That's secret pain.
好啊,那一定是个隐藏的非常深的秘密,连我自己都不知道.
Well, that must be a very deep secret, 'cause I don't know about it.
嗯.没有什么能比你的笔迹更能泄漏你心底的秘密.
Hmm. There's nothing more naked than your handwriting.
没有字是挨着线的，看到吗?
See how nothing's quite touching the line ?
-那是空虚.  -呃, 我们都知道就是这样.
- That's vanity. - Well, we certainly know that's true.
你有兄弟吗?
[ Dickie ]Do you have any brothers ?
没有.
No.
没有兄弟,没有姐妹.
No brothers,no sisters.
我也一样.
Me neither.
玛吉也一样.
Nor does Marge.
都是独子.
All only children.
这意味着什么?
What does that mean ?
意味着我们从未和人共用一个浴池.
Means we've never shared a bath.
我很冷.我能进来吗?
And I'm cold.Can I get in ?
不能.
No.
我不是说和你一起.
I didn't mean with you in it.
好吧.
Okay.
进来吧.我也该去修修边幅了.
Get in. I'm like a prune anyway.
这是我.不过是年代久远罢了.
It is me.It's an old picture.
每次都是这样! "是你吗?看起来不像你."
Every time ! "Is it you ?It doesn't look like you."
天!
God !
信..格林立夫写给瑞普雷的.
Letters..Greenleaf and for Ripley.
噢.弗朗. "我想念你.你什么时候回来?
Ooh. Fran. "I miss you.When are you coming home ?
别告诉我你在那儿过得有多开心.
Stop telling me what an incredible time you're having.
-或是你又多爱迪克.   -哇噢!
- How much you love Dickie. - Whoo !
爱玛吉和蒙吉."
And Marge and Mongibello."
这封信，我认为是你父亲写的.
And this one, I think, is from your father.
[Dickie Vocalizing: Jazz]
-让我看看.他说了些什么?  -他开始不耐烦了.
- Let me see it. What does he say ? - He's getting impatient.
他想让我保证你能在感恩节前赶回去.
He wants me to reassure him that you're going to be home by Thanksgiving.
你得买件新外套了，真的.
You've got to get a new jacket. Really.
老穿一件衣服，你一定觉得很厌烦了.
You must be sick of wearing the same clothes.
我不能.我不能老花你父亲的钱.
I can't. I can't keep spending your father's money.
我喜欢你的责任感.
I love how responsible you are.
我爸爸会让你做个首席会计之类的工作.
My dad should make you chief accountant or something.
或者等我接管的时候, 我想那是不可能发生了,我聘你.
Or when I take over,which is never, I will.
好的. 当你接管的时候,反正遥遥无期,我接受.
Okay. When you take over,which is never, I'll accept.
让我给你买件外套. 当我们一起去罗马的时候,那儿有个极好的地方...
Let me buy you a jacket. When we get to Rome, there's a great place...
-巴蒂斯多尼.   -巴蒂斯多尼.
- Battistoni.  - Battistoni.
[ Italian ]
罗马,我们带汤姆去罗马
Roma, we're taking Tom to Roma
我们一起去罗马
We’re going to a-Roma
[ Chattering in Italian ]
早上好.漂亮的毛衣.
Buongiorno.Nice sweater.
我们应该到哪儿雇辆马车去广场?
Where do we get a carrozza for the Forum ?
-我们能雇他们吗?   -放松点.
- Can we just hire any of them ? - Relax.
放松点!
Relax !
只是今天一天要做的事情太多了.
It’s just there's so much to do in a single day.
最重要的事是我们该去哪儿吃饭.我希望弗雷迪已经订好了位子.
The most important question is where to eat. I hope Freddie made a reservation.
费雷迪?
Freddie ?
费雷迪.费雷迪·迈尔斯.
Freddie.Freddie Miles.
是费雷迪组织的科尔蒂纳滑雪游.
Freddie's organizing the Cortina skiing trip.
噢.
Oh.
噢,他来了.
Oh, here he is.
[ Tires Screech ]
-弗朗西斯科!   -你好吗?
- Frederico ! - Comestai ?
- [ Italian ]
哦,天,你是不是看到每个女人都想上一次?
Oh, God, don't you want to fuck every woman you see just once ?
- 就一次?   - 当然.就一次.你好.
- Only once ?  - Absolutely. Once. Ciao.
-汤姆·瑞普雷,弗雷迪·迈尔斯.  -汤姆.
- Tom Ripley, Freddie Miles. - Tom.
我是指,嗨,如果我这也叫晚,想想看她老公会怎么说.
I mean, hey, if I'm late,think what her husband's saying.
-你看起来棒极了.   -和往常一样.
- You look gorgeous. - As always.
那么,吃饭.
So, mangiare.
好. 我在法布里兹奥订了张桌子.汤米.
Si. I got us a table outside at Fabrizio's. Tommy.
太棒了.我告诉你,
[Dickie]Outstanding. I tell you,
-我快被蒙吉那个小地方给困死了.  -我知道，我去过那儿.
- I'm so cabin-crazy with Mongi. - I know. I was there.
[Jazz]
看,汤姆,我们得去一个俱乐部见见弗雷迪的一群朋友.
Look, Tom, we got to go to a club and meet some friends of Freddie’s.
如果你想去游玩，最好现在就去叫辆车。
The best thing is, if you want to be a tourist, grab a cab now,
我会和你在火车站碰头.
and I'll meet you at the railway station.
哪家俱乐部?
What club ?
弗雷迪和滑雪团一些人安排的.
Freddie's arranged it with some of the skiing crowd.
你想来就来吧，不过我以为你想去观光.
Come if you want, but I thought you wanted to go sightseeing.
我是想,也许还会去买件外套，你说过的.
I do, and then maybe get the jacket and what have you.
迪克!你得来听听这个.
Dick !You gotta hear this.
听着,先穿我的，等我们回来再说.
Listen, just take one of mine when we get back.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
好吧!
Come on !
再见.玩得开心点,好吗?
Ciao.Have fun, okay ?
[Knocking]
你说过要确定你不会错过火车，8：00发车.
You said to make sure you didn't miss the train. Leaves at 8:00.
[ Snickers ]
玩得开心点.
Have a good time.
再见,汤米.
See ya, Tommy.
[ Whistles ]
[Whistle Blows]
如果我对她来说还有意义
If I meant anything to her
我会勇敢,我将会对她唱这首歌
I'd be brave, and here’s the song I'd bring to her
我会对她唱道
I'd sing to her
也许我是唯一一个
May I be the only one
对她说
To say I
在我第一次见到你的时候
Really fell in love the day I
我就深深地爱上了你
First set eyes on you
-我能否   -你在干吗?
-  May I  - What are you doing ?
哦.我只是在自娱自乐罢了.
Oh. I was just amusing myself.
-对不起.   -我希望你能脱下我的衣服.
- Sorry. - I wish you'd get out of my clothes.
-你是不是还穿了我的鞋?  -你说过我可以先穿你的外套...
- Do you have my shoes on too ? - You said I could pick out a jacket...
你能不能回你自己的房间脱?
Did you get undressed in your own room ?
我以为你错过了火车.
Thought you missed the train.
弗雷迪用车带我回来的.
Freddie drove me back in his car.
-弗雷迪也来了吗?   -他就在楼下.
- Is Freddie here ? - He's downstairs.
我刚刚只是在瞎胡闹。
I was just fooling around.
别再说了.我刚刚只是在瞎胡闹.
Don't say anything.I was just fooling around.
对不起.
Sorry.
天.在意大利就一件灯芯绒外套.
[Freddie]God. A corduroy jacket in Italy.
-早上好,汤姆.   -早上好.
- [Marge] Good morning, Tom.  - Morning.
-来一起坐.
- [ Chuckles ]- Come join us.
嗨.我也想要你这份工作,汤米.
Hey. I want this job of yours, Tommy.
我刚刚还在说,你住在意大利,
I was just saying,you live in Italy,
你住的是迪克的,你吃的是迪克的,
you stay at Dickie's house,you eat Dickie's food,
你穿的是他的,他父亲还得给你付帐.
you wear his clothes,and his father picks up the tab.
如果你不想干了,
[Chuckles]If you get bored,
告诉我,我来做.
you let me know, 'cause I'll do it.
-我来做.-潜到底!
- I'll do it.  - [Dickie] To the mainland!
你真应该下来.太棒了.
You really should go in.It's marvelous.
我很好.
I'm fine.
[ Dickie Shouting ]
你还好吗?
Are you okay ?
很好.
Sure.
和迪克一起是这样的...
The thing with Dickie...
就像是阳光为你闪耀,金光灿烂.
It's like the sun shines on you, and it's glorious.
如果他遗忘了你，就会寒彻骨.
And then he forgets you and it's very, very cold.
我正在学会适应.
So I'm learning.
当他注意你时,你会感觉整个世界只属于你一人.
When you have his attention, you feel you're the only person in the world.
这就是为什么人人都爱他.
That's why everybody loves him.
总是这样.每当一个人进入他的生活...
It's always the same. Whenever someone new comes into his life...
弗雷迪,福斯托,彼得 史密斯-金斯利.
Freddie, Fausto,Peter Smith-Kingsley.
他是个大好人.你见过他吗?
He's wonderful.Have you met him ?
特别是你.
Especially you.
这还只是男孩子.
And that’s just the boys.
[ Dickie,Freddie Shouting ]
快来抓他!快来抓他!
Come get him !Come get him !
告诉我,为什么每次男人在一起玩闹,
Tell me, why is itthat when men play,
他们总是完一些杀来杀去的游戏?
they always play at killing each other ?
他想淹死我!他想淹死我!
[Dickie] He's drowning me!He's drowning me!
-关于科尔蒂纳的是我很抱歉,顺便说一句. -科尔蒂纳怎么了?
- I'm sorry about Cortina, by the way. - What about Cortina ?
他还没...迪克还没告诉过你吗?
Didn't...Didn't-Didn't Dick say ?
他对弗雷迪说过,然而-然而明显他还没有...
[Sighs] He spoke to Freddie,and-and apparently...
这是行不通的.
it's not going to work out.
这是因为其他所有人都会滑雪,
It's because everyone else can ski,
你不会自然会产生些影响,
and it affects where you stay,
来吧,弗雷迪.
[ Dickie ]Come on, Freddie.
至少留下来过圣母节.
At least stick around for the Festival of the Madonna.
-全镇的人都会出来..  -我不这样想.
- The whole town comes out..  - I don’t think so.
我自己在罗马,嗯,有个圣母节.你不如和我一起来?
I have my own, uh, Madonna back in Rome.Why don’t you come back with me ?
狂多的女人.噢.
A lot of ladies.Ooh.
[ Chuckles ]
-噢,天.  -你来掌舵?
- Oh, God. - You want to take over ?
好的,没问题.
Yeah, sure.
就对着卡普里的方向就行了.绕过岩石.
Just point her at Capri.Avoid the rocks.
你去哪儿?
Where are you going ?
安抚玛吉.
Marge maintenance.
是啊-是啊.
Aye-aye.
[Marge, Dickie Murmuring]
别.
[ Marge ]Don't.
[ Scoffs ]
-迪克..
- [ Marge ] Dickie.. - [ Dickie Moaning ]
汤米.偷窥的感觉如何?
Tommy.How's the peeping ?
Tommy,how's the peeping ?
汤米,汤米,汤米,汤米,汤米.
Tommy, Tommy,Tommy, Tommy, Tommy.
[Chanting, indistinct]
[People Applauding]
[Chanting Continues]
[ Screaming in Italian ]
[ People Shouting ]
就没人叫辆救护车吗?
Is someone getting an ambulance ?
-就没人叫辆救护车吗?
- Is someone getting an ambulance ? - [ Wailing ]
[People Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
[ Shouting, indistinct ]
为什么要争执?那不是她的未婚夫吗?
What's the fight about ?That's her fiancé, isn't it ?
-我不知道，你干吗问我?  -他们是在指责他吗?
- I don't know. Why are you asking me ? - Are they blaming him ?
为什么叫一辆救护车得花一个小时?
How can it take an hour to find an ambulance ?
她早就死了,亲爱的,不是吗?所以我想...
She was already dead, darling,wasn't she ? So I suppose...
我不知道为什么人们说这个国家是个文明古国.
I don't know why people say this country is civilized.
- 迪克!  - 根本就不是.根本就是个原始社会.
- Dickie ! - It isn't. It's fucking primitive.
我去看看到底是怎么回事.
I'll go see what's the matter.
我去.
I'll go.
[Saxophone]
我知道你为什么伤心.
[Tom]I know why you’re upset.
我知道希尔维那,迪克.
I know about Silvana, Dickie.
我知道你和希尔维那之间的关系.
I know about you and Silvana.
我们怎么了?
What about us ?
你不需要来收拾!不需要!
You don't have to clean up ! Really !
-比如什么?   -算了吧.
- Like what ? - Forget it.
她怀孕了.你知道吗?
She was pregnant.Did you know that ?
希尔维那怀孕了.
Silvana was pregnant.
你知道这在这种地方意味着什么吗?
Do you know what that means in a place like this ?
我已经准备好了接受指责.
I'm prepared to take the blame.
-你说什么呢?   -你一直对我这么好.
- What are you talking about ? - You've been so good to me.
你就像是我从未有过的兄弟.我就像是你从未有过的兄弟
You're the brother I never had.I'm the brother you never had.
我可以为你做任何事,迪克.
I would do anything for you, Dickie.
她来求我帮助她.
She came to me for help.
她需要钱.
She needed money.
我没帮她.我没帮她.
I didn't help her.I didn't help her.
现在她自杀了，这全是我的错.
Now she’s drowned herself,and it's my fault.
我不会说出去的...
I'm not going to say anything...
包括玛吉，包括警察，任何人.
to Marge, to the police or anybody.
这是我们俩人之间的秘密，迪克.
It's a secret between us, Dickie.
我会保守秘密的.
And I'll keep it.
"亲爱的汤姆.看到迪克在你去了之后...
[Tom Reading] “Dear Tom.in view of the fact Dickie shows...
并不比以前更想回家...如此这般，如此这般...
no more signs of coming home than before you went...” blah, blah, blah...
嗯...
Um...
"我希望这次旅行给你带来了一定快乐...
"I hope that the trip has afforded you some pleasure...
虽然目标并没有达成.
despite the failure of its main objective.
你也无需认为还对我们负有任何义务."
You no longer should consider yourself obligated to us in any way."
不能怪他.
Can't blame him.
不会一直这样下去的,汤姆.
You could hardly expect this to go on forever, Tom.
呃, 你可以再写信.
Well, you can write again.
-特别是我们现在已经成兄弟了.   -我不能.
- Especially now we're brothers. - I can't.
我怎么能这么做,会很丢脸.
How can l,in all decency.
你自己说过.你在这里花的钱都是我父亲的.
You said it yourself.It’s my dad's money you're spending.
我们玩得很开心，不是吗?
We've had a great run though, haven't we ?
呃,我们还是要去威尼斯.我们可以按原计划去.
Well, we'll still go to Venice.We could stick to that plan.
我不这样认为,汤姆.
I don't think so, Tom.
你无法支付旅费,不是吗?
You can’t pay your own way, can you ?
我们都该往前了.
It’s time we all moved on.
我受不了蒙吉.特别是现在,当一切都..
I'm sick of Mongi.Especially now, with everything..
我真的很想搬去北方.
I really want to move to the north.
我下星期要去圣雷默看看.
I need to check out San Remo next week.
给游艇找个新地方.
Find somewhere new to keep the boat.
当然，如果你能来就太好了,如果你和我一起去圣雷默.
It would be great, though, if you came with me to San Remo.
哪儿有个很棒的爵士节.我们可以很体面地告别.
There's a great jazz festival.We could say good-bye in style.
你觉得呢?
What do you think ?
我们最后的旅行!
Our last trip !
当然.
Sure.
[Speaking Italian]
你干吗老那么扭你的脖子?
Why do you do that thing with your neck ?
怎么扭了?
What thing ?
在火车上,你老是这么干.
On trains, you always
do that thing.
阴森森的.
Spooky.
阴森森...
Spook... k.k..k.k..k.k..
[ Imitating Jazz Percussion ]
阴森森.
Spooky.
[Cymbals]
[Jazz ]
噢!
Oh !
我不是告诉过你圣雷默很疯狂?
Didn't I tell you San Remo was crazy ?
这才像嘛!来啊!
This is more like it !Come on !
[ Ends ]
谢谢.
Grazie.
敬蒙吉，敬我生命中最快乐的时光.
To Mongibello and the happiest days of my life.
敬蒙吉,你今晚很开心.
To Mongi.You're cheerful tonight.
我突然很高兴快回去了.
I'm suddenly quite happy to be going back.
在普林斯顿时我认识你吗，汤姆?
Did I know you at Princeton, Tom ?
我不觉得我认识你,不是吗?
I don't think I did,did I ?
-为什么突然一下问起这个?  -没什么.
- Why are you asking all of a sudden ? - No reason.
也许是因为你要离开了,我猜.我不认为你是打那儿毕业的.
Because you're leaving, I guess.I don't think you were there.
- 为什么?  - 我是在恭维你.
- Why ? - I mean it as a compliment.
你的品位很高.
You've got such great taste.
普林斯顿那帮俗人什么都尝试所以没品.
Most of the thugs at Princeton had tasted everything and had no taste.
我经常这样说,"美国奶油:又厚又油."
I used to say,"the cream of America: rich and thick."
弗雷迪就是一个典型.
Freddie's the perfect example.
那我就当恭维来听了.
Then I'll take it as a compliment.
我就知道!我就知道.
I knew it !I knew it.
玛吉和我打了个赌.
Marge and I had a bet.
你是否真喜欢爵士,
Do you even like jazz,
或者只是为了迎合我?
or was that for my benefit ?
-我当然喜欢.  -噢,太好了!
- I've gotten to like it.  - Oh, yes !
我喜欢你和你所有的生活方式.
I’ve gotten to like everything about the way you live.
这事关爱.
It's one big love affair.
如果你知道我以前在纽约的生活..
If you knew my life back home in New York..
我想放弃吹萨克斯.
I'm thinkin' of givin' up the sax.
你觉得做鼓手怎么样?
What do you think about the drums ?
-什么?   -太酷了.
- What ? - So cool.
我明天打算租艘船,四处看看.
I'm gonna rent a boat tomorrow,take a look around.
我当初就是这么找到蒙吉的.
This is how I found my place in Mongi.
租艘船...
Took a boat out...
绕着海岸行驶,
around the bay,
遇到第一个我喜欢的,
first thing I liked,
我就要它.
I got it.
-哇!    -好了,迪克.别太疯了.
- Whoa ! - Come on, Dickie. Don’t go crazy.
-迪克.放慢速度!  -抓紧.
- Dickie. Slow down !  - [ Laughing ] Hold on.
等一下!要翻了!噢,天啊!
Wait a minute !It's gonna tip ! Oh, God !
停下!救命!救命!停下!
Stop it ! Somebody !Somebody ! Stop it !
[ Shouting ]
噢,我爱这里!
Oh, I love it here !
我爱这里!我爱这里!
I love it here !I'm gonna move here !
多美.
Beautiful.
[ Imitating Cymbal Percussion ]
我想告诉你我的计划.
I want to tell you my plan.
-告诉我吧.   -是这样,我想...
- So tell me. - Well, I thought...
我想在新年时自费回来.
I'd come back in the new year under my own steam.
-真的?回意大利?   -当然.
- Really ? To Italy ? - Of course.
我想了想,只是说说而已,
And I figured, just for argument's sake,
比如说我找了一套房子.
say I got a place.
比如说我们分摊房租,
Or say we split the rent on a house,
我能找一份工作,或者,更好些,
I could get a job,or, better still,
如果我在罗马租了一套房子,那我们想去那里去那里,
if I got a place in Rome,and then when we're there,
想在这里在这里.
we could be there, and when we're here,we could be here.
-我不这样想.   -尤其是考虑到玛吉
- I don't think so. - Particularly with the Marge problem.
你就说是我的错好了.
You just blame me.
-玛吉和我就要结婚了.  -怎么会?
- Marge and I are getting married. - How ?
-怎么会?  -昨天你还在和其他女孩调情.
- How ?  - Yesterday, you were ogling girls.
今天你就要结婚了?太荒谬了.
Today you're getting married ?That's absurd.
-我爱玛吉.  -你爱我.你也没和我结婚啊.
- I love Marge. - You love me. You're not marrying me.
-汤姆,我不爱你. -不,我并不是威胁的意思.
- Tom, I don't love you. - No, I don't mean that as a threat.
老实说,我..我有点希望你能离开.
To be honest, I'm..I’m a little relieved you're going.
我觉得这段时间我们已经看够对方了.
I think we've seen enough of each other for a while.
-什么?  -你有时就像条吸血水蛭!
- What ? - You can be a leech !
你知道!
You know that !
而且...令人厌烦.
And... it’s boring.
你有时真的很令人厌烦.
You can be quite boring.
可笑的是,我没有假装...
The funny thing is,I'm not pretending...
去成为别人,你却一直这样.
to be somebody else,and you are.
-令人厌烦.  -我对你一直都很...
-Boring.   -I’ve been absolutely honest with you...
坦诚相待.
about my feelings.
-令人厌烦.-但是你...首先,
- Boring.- But you...First of all,
我知道你在隐藏一些事.
I know there's something.
举个例子,那一晚,当我们在下棋的时候,就很明显.
That evening, when we played chess,for instance, it was obvious.
-哪一晚? -对你来说表现出来会很危险.
- What evening ? - It's too dangerous for you to take on.
噢,不,不.我们是兄弟.
Oh, no, no.We're brothers.
嗨.然后你就和玛吉做哪些肮脏的事...干她...
Hey. And then you do this sordid thing with Marge...fucking her...
在船上,我们还都得听着,
on the boat, while we all have to listen,
根本就是种折磨.
which was excruciating.
你总是用下半身来思考...现在你倒是要结婚了.
And you follow your cock around like a...And now you're getting married.
不,我太迷惑了.原谅我.
No, I’m bewildered.Forgive me.
你欺骗玛吉却还要和她结婚.
You're lying to Marge and then you're getting married to her.
你甩了席尔瓦那,毁了所有人...你想吹萨克斯.
You're knocking up Sylvana, ruining everybody....You want to play the sax.
你想做鼓手.是这样吗,迪克?你到底是什么...
You want to play the drums. Which is it,Dickie ? What are you actually...
你又是什么?嗯?一个三流乞丐?你又是什么?
Who are you ? Huh ?Some third-class mooch ? Who are you ?
谁给你权力来教训我的?
Who are you to say anything to me ?
Who are you to tell me anything ?
其实,我真的,真的无法忍受和你一起呆在这条船上.
Actually, I really, really do not want to be on this boat with you.
- 你不动我就动不了.  - 住嘴.住嘴.
- I can't move without you moving. - Shut up. Shut up.
是你让我起鸡皮疙瘩.是你让我起鸡皮疙瘩.
It gives me the creeps.You give me the creeps.
-你住嘴.  -没有你在一旁像小姑娘一样叫“迪克，迪克”
- You shut up. - I can't move without "Dickie, Dickie,"
我就动不了.
Like a little girl all the time.
住嘴!
Shut up !
噢,天啊,迪克.
Oh, God, Dickie.
-看在上帝的份上.  -噢..噢.上帝啊!
- God's sake.   - Oh...Oh God !
没事的.没事的.
Okay. Okay.
我们得给你...好...
We have to get you.. Okay..[ Screams ]
我要杀了你!杀了你!
I'm gonna kill you !Kill you !
[ Screaming ]
你死定了!
You're dead !
住手!住手!求你了!求你了!
Stop ! Stop !Please ! Please !
-快住手!快住手!
- [ Screaming ]- Stop it ! Stop !
-迪克,放开!-我要杀了你!
- Dickie, let go !- I’ll kill you!
住手!住手!住手!
Stop ! Stop !Stop !
[ Panting ]
你好.我能拿我的钥匙吗?
Hi. Can I have my key, please ?
当然.
Of course.
你一定很冷吧.呃,格林立夫先生,是吗?
You must be very cold.Uh, Signor Greenleaf, yes ?
不.我是...
No. I'm...
[Keyboard Clacking]
-你好,玛吉.
- Hello, Marge.- [ Screams ]
汤姆!
Tom ![ Chuckles ]
你吓着我了!
You startled me !
-对不起.你怎么样?   -你回来了!
- Sorry. How are you ?  - You're back!
-你的书进展得还顺利吧?   -是啊.
- Your book going well ?  - Yes.
很顺利,谢谢.
I'm on a good streak,thank you.
我只是...一直很安静地望着你.
I was just...Looking at you. So quiet.
迪克在哪儿?
[ Chuckles ]Where's Dickie ?
我想他计划在罗马多呆几天.
I think he's planning on staying in Rome for a few days.
罗马?呃.他说为什么了吗?
Rome ? Ahh.Did he say why ?
我不了解迪克.你也知道.
I don't understand Dickie.Your guess is as good as mine.
什么意思?
What does that mean ?
噢,某一天我被邀请去滑雪,第二天就不要我去了.
Oh, one day I'm invited skiing,the next day I'm not.
某一天,我们是一家人,第二天他就想独自呆着.
One day, we're one family,then the next day he wants to be alone.
你告诉我.
You tell me.
那是他说的吗?他想一个人呆着?
Is that what he said ?He wants to be alone ?
他一直想着你.他让我给你这个.
He was thinking of you.He asked me to deliver this.
谢谢.
Thank you.[ Chuckles ]
他知道我喜欢这种香水.
He knows I love this.
-为什么他不等回来再送给我呢.我..  -任务一:
- But why it couldn't have waited. I.. - Errand number one.:
转交给玛吉香水.
deliver Marge's perfume.
任务二:
Errand number two:
收拾些衣服，再带上他那支宝贝萨克斯.
pack some clothes and his precious saxophone.
他打算住多久?
How long is he staying for ?
问我也白问.我猜我们都被抛弃了.
Search me.I guess we're abandoned.
见鬼!
Goddamn it !
你还好吗?
[ Tom ]Are you okay?
这是迪克夹在香水盒里的一封信.
There was a letter from Dickie in with my perfume.
你知道这次并不是多呆几天.
You realize it's more than just a few days.
他想着要搬到罗马去.
He's thinking of moving to Rome.[ Sniffles ]
事实上是,
The thing is,
他离开前一天的晚上,我们...
the night before he left, we...
我们商量要搬到一起住...
we talked about moving together...
北面的某个地方,我猜我...
somewhere north,and I suppose I...
是在结婚这件事上给了他太多的压力.
put some pressure on him about getting married.
我只是...
I just...[ Sobs ]
只是我有可能把他吓走了.
I just might have scared him off.
当我们一起躺在床上...
There's a side to him...
我望着他的侧面...
when our heads are on the pillow...
我知道再没有人能像他这样温柔.
I know no one else sees that's so tender.
我想我该跟随你到罗马去问问他。
I think I should come with you to Rome and confront him.
他讨厌被质问.
He hates being confronted.
我认为你是对的.
I think you’re right.
谢谢.住店.
Grazie.Checking in.
住店.
Checking in.
- 瑞普雷先生?   - 对.
- Signor Ripley ?  - It's me.
格林立夫先生.
Signor Greenleaf.
当然是格林立夫先生.欢迎回来.
Of course.Welcome back.
谢谢.
Thank you.
喂?
[ Woman ] Pronto ?
是的, 我想打个电话给高道尼旅馆.
Yes, I'd like to telephone the Hotel Goldoni.
- 好的, 先生. - 我找托马斯·瑞普雷.
- Si, signor. - I want to speak to Thomas Ripley.
- 瑞普雷? 知道了.  - 是的. 谢谢.
- Ripley ? Subito.  - Yes. Grazie.
- 喂.
- [Phone Buzzes] - Pronto.
格林立夫先生,瑞普雷先生不在.
Signor Greenleaf,Signor Ripley's not there.
- 他不在?   - 不在, 先生.
- He's not there ?  - No, signor.
好吧, 我留个言.
Well, I would like to leave a message.
- 他不在那儿? 那我留言吧.   - 不在, 先生.
- He's not there ? I'll leave a message.  - No, signor.
- 接到你的电话.  - 接到你的电话.
- Got your call. - Got your call.
- 今晚共餐... - 今晚共餐...
- Dinner tonight... - Dinner tonight...
- 似乎不错.     - 似乎不错.
- sounds fine. - sounds fine.
- 瑞普雷. 瑞普雷.   - 瑞普雷.
- Ripley. Ripley.   - Ripley.
- 迪克·格林立夫.     - 迪克·格林立夫.
- Dickie Greenleaf.  - [ Woman ] Dickie Greenleaf.
- 是的. 格林立夫.   - 格林立夫.
- Yes. Greenleaf.   - Greenleaf.
在格兰得旅馆.
At the Grand.
我想在这个钱包上加点装饰.
[Tom] And I’d like to have this wallet embossed.
我不知道这个词用英文怎么说.
I don't know the word in Italian.
装饰一下. 当然可以,格林立夫先生.
Embossed. Of course,Signor Greenleaf.
谢谢.
Thank you.
迪克!我是....
Dickie !It's...
- 天啊.     - 梅瑞迪斯.
- Oh, my gosh.  - Meredith.
- 你好!   - 你好. 请进. 请进.
- Ciao !  - Ciao. Come in. Come in.
不过你会和那些美国佬一起去滑雪，对吧?
But you're going skiing with those Yankees, aren't you ?
- 什么?   - 圣诞节. 去科尔蒂纳滑雪.
- What ?  - At Christmas. To Cortina.
- 和弗雷迪·迈尔斯.   - 你是怎么知道的?
- With Freddie Miles. - How did you know that ?
噢! 人人都认识弗雷迪·迈尔斯.
Oh ! Everybody knows Freddie Miles.
弗雷迪在罗马?
Is Freddie in Rome ?
- 现在?   - 对.
- Now ?   - Yeah.
噢, 我可不这样想.
Oh, I don't think so.
不过我...不过我见过他,当然, 我们还聊了几句.
But l...But I've met him,of course, and we've chatted.
而且我还知道你...
And I know about you...
和玛吉两人在蒙吉.
and Marge in Mongi.
你还真是只靠不住的小老鼠啊.
What an unreliable rat you are.
当然, 弗雷迪说你是只小老鼠.
Well, Freddie said you were a rat.
现在我想到了,
And I thought to myself,
"为什么他旅行时以'R'作为姓名首字母"
"Ah, now I know why
he travels under 'R."'
我离开了玛吉,梅瑞迪斯.
I've left Marge,Meredith.
离开了蒙吉.
And Mongi.
- 所以现在这只老鼠在罗马了.   - 噢，太遗憾了.
- So the rat's here in Rome.  - Oh, I'm sorry.
噢, 别觉得遗憾, 别.我从未这样开心过。
Oh, don't be sorry, no.I've never been happier.
我...我觉得自己好像被赋予了新生命.
I...I feel like I've been handed a new life.
事实是如果你一生都很富有,
The truth is that if you’ve had money your entire life,
你要么就像我们这样蔑视金钱...对吗?
either you despise it,which we do...agreed ?
你也只有在和其它那些富有又同样蔑视金钱的人一起时...
You're only truly comfortable around other people...
才会真正感觉舒服.
who have it and despise it.
我知道.
I know.
我还从来没向任何人坦白过这一点.
I've never admitted that to anyone.
[ Chattering in Italian ]
因为我的朋友格林立夫先生,格林立夫和我,
[Meredith] Because my friend Mr. Greenleaf, Signor Greenleaf and I,
打算花钱搞个小狂欢.
are on a little spending spree.
- 明白了.   - 我们的行为不太检点.
- [Man] I see.  - We're behaving very badly.
噢, 我喜欢意大利的纸币. 色调很暗.不会让我觉得有罪恶感.
Oh, I love Italian money. So dark.Doesn't make you feel guilty.
- 谢...谢.    - 谢谢.
- Gr-r-razie. - Thank you.
我不想要太多大钞.没人愿意找零.
I don't want too many large bills.No one will change them.
完全没问题,格林立夫先生.
Tutto bene,Signor Greenleaf.
[ Counting in Italian ]
[Italian]
- 我真的很喜欢这一件.  - 我想把它也买下来.
- I really like this too. - I think I'm having that too.
[ Italian ]
- 明天.
- Tomorrow.- [ Italian ]
- 再见.   - 再见. 噢!
- Arrivederci.  - Arrivederci. Oops !
- 再见.  - 再见.
- Ciao.  - Ciao.
我知道你是个爵士迷,不过你就一定恨歌剧吗?
I know you're a jazz fiend, but do you absolutely hate the opera ?
我一直想...我一直想...
I've...I've...
解决掉我的几张门票.
been trying to give my tickets away.
明天的. 不过如果你愿意被硬拖着去的话...
It's tomorrow. But if you were prepared to be dragged...
你可以拉我去.
You could drag me.
[ Opera: Italian ]
[Shot Fires]
[Body Thuds]
[Audience Applauding]
费奥多·卡利亚宾.全是俄国男中音.
Feodor Chaliapin.It's the whole Russian baritone.
非常感谢你今晚邀请我来.
Thank you so much for inviting me tonight.
你受的了?我们听说你是弗雷迪的朋友.
Can you bear it ?We hear you are a friend of Freddie's.
他在胸前纹了"我恨歌剧"几个字.
He has "I hate opera" tattooed on his chest.
弗雷迪胸前足够刻上整个歌剧剧本了.
There's room for a whole libretto on Freddie's chest.
我确信我们见过面.
I'm sure we've met before.
我确信我们见过面.你觉得呢, 泰德?
I was sure we'd met before.Weren't you, Ted ?
迪克是赫伯特·格林立夫的儿子.
Dick is Herbert Greenleaf's boy.
- 我知道.   - 对, 我想我们见过面.
- I know.   - Yes, I think we have.
一分钟前你们还是孩子,  一眨眼功夫连纹身都纹上了.
One minute you people are children,and the next you're getting tattooed.
- 干杯.   - 干杯.
- Cheers.  - Cheers.
干杯.
Cheers.
- 请让一下.   - 请.
- Excuse me.  - Prego.
噢!对不起.
Oh !Excuse me.
- 你好.   - 你好.
- Hello.  - Hello.
- 汤姆!   - 玛吉!
- Tom !   - Marge !
你好吗?你来罗马干什么?
How are you ?What are you doing in Rome ?
- 他在这儿吗? 你是和迪克一起的吗?  - 不. 嗯, 不是.
- Is he here ? Are you with Dickie ? - No. Um, no.
嗯, 你好.嗯, 我是汤姆·瑞普雷.
Um, hello.
Um, I'm Tom Ripley.
彼得·史密斯·金斯利.我从玛吉和迪克那儿听说过不少你的事.
Peter Smith-Kingsley. I've heard all about you from Marge and Dickie.
- 果然如此.  - 没..没戴眼镜.
- Ditto.   - No..No glasses.
那么, 你把他藏哪儿了?他真是不可理喻, 不是吗?
So, where are you hiding him ?He's impossible, isn't he ?
他真不在这?
Is he really not here ?
玛吉, 你知道迪克在胸前刻着"我恨歌剧" 几个字.
Marge, you know Dickie has"I hate opera" tattooed on his chest.
- 我以为你们去了威尼斯.  - 是呀, 后来怎么样了?
- I thought you were going to Venice.  - Yes, what happened with that ?
我听说你一心想来.
I heard you were desperate to come.
我还期盼着能带你去划船.
I was rather looking forward to rowing you around.
- 是啊，我是很想来着.
- [Bell Ringing] - I am. I really am.
我一直在旅行,但好像就是到不了那么北的地方.
I've been traveling, and I just can't seem to get that far north.
好吧, 你得快点,否则我们都得沉了.
Well, you should hurry,before we sink.
这样吧, 我给你我的电话号码.
Look, let me give you the telephone number.
看那儿. 噢, 看.那不是梅瑞迪斯吗.
There. Oh, look.There's Meredith.
梅瑞迪斯. 她姓什么来着,玛吉? 那些开纺织厂的人.
Meredith. What's her name,Marge ? The textile people.
嗯, 想想. 我们一些人还在她家度过圣诞.
Um, come on. Some of us spent Christmas at her house.
我不认识她.
I don't know her.
他从未打过电话.连信都很少写.
He hasn't called.He's hardly written.
就是写点神秘小纸条,你知道吗?
Just these cryptic notes, you know ?
- 你不能就这样甩了别人.
- You don't just dump people. - [Bell Rings]
这样吧, 我们是呆会见,或者你是和其它人一起来的?
Look, will we see you later,or are you with people ?
- 嗯, 呆会不行.  - 这样吧, 明天怎么样?
- Uh, I can't later. - Well, how about tomorrow ?
好啊, 嗯,早上怎么样?
Yes, uh,maybe in the morning ?
你知道斯帕格纳广场边的蒂内利咖啡店吗?
Do you know Cafe Dinelli at the Piazza di Spagna ?
- 我知道那广场. 几点?   - 10:30?
- I know the Piazza. What time ?  - 10:30 ?
- 我们会准时到的.   - 好的.
- We'll be there.   - Okay.
那明天见, 玛吉?
So I'll see you in the morning, Marge ?
10.:30   很高兴认识你.
10.:30   Very nice to meet you.
我也一样.
[Peter]And you.
来吧.
Come on.
来吧.让我们进去.
Come on.Let's go back in.
我不明白汤姆为什么还在罗马.
I don't understand why Tom's still in Rome.
- 我们走吧.   - 我还以为你很喜欢歌剧呢.
- [ Whispering ] Let's go. - I thought you were enjoying yourself.
让我们乘马车看看月亮.
Let's take a carrozza and look at the moon.
你疯了吗?外面冷极了.
Are you crazy ?It's freezing out there.
来吧. 我得和你谈谈.就我们俩.
Come on. I need to talk to you.Just the two of us.
好吧.
[Meredith]Okay.
请别担心.
[ Meredith ]Don't worry, please.
别担心.
Don't worry.
你真的很善解人意. 我...
You're such a palto understand. I...
就好像玛吉无时无刻不在这儿.当我望着你的脸庞,
It's like Marge is here right now. I look at you,
就看到了她的脸.
and I see her face.
我就是不能...不管我对你的感觉到底如何...
And I can't... No matter what I'm feeling towards you...
不用解释. 我完全...理解. 当...
No. I absolutely...understand. Of c...
要不然, 你会抗拒我的.
Otherwise, you'd be fighting me off.
打走你.
Beating you away.
不过我们明天能见面吗?
But will you meet me tomorrow ?
就是来个正式告别,你知道, 在白天,
Just to say good-bye properly,you know, in the daylight,
不像现在这样.
so it's not just this.
当然. 梅瑞迪斯,很抱歉.我当然会去见你.
Of course. Meredith, I'm sorry.Of course I'll meet you.
你永远都应该把痛苦留给白天.
You should always save pain for daylight.
不如我们明天早上一起去蒂内利喝咖啡?
Why don't we have coffee in the morning at Dinelli's ?
噢, 就在西班牙阶梯旁边.
Uh, by the Spanish Steps.
完全正确. 10:30 ?
Exactly. 10:30 ?
- 10:15.  - 好的.
- 10:15.  - Okay.
好的.
Okay.
[Bell Tolling]
[Tolling Continues]
[ Italian ]
[ Chattering, indistinct ]
- 谢谢.   - 彼得?
- [ Peter ] Grazie.  - Peter ?
你好.我是梅瑞迪斯·罗吉.
Hello.It's Meredith Logue.
当然是你.梅瑞迪斯, 你好. 对不起.
[Peter] Of course it is.Meredith, hello. Sorry.
- 我还没睡醒呢. 你好吗?   - 你好吗?
- I was half asleep. How are you ?  - How are you ?
这是玛吉·舍伍德,梅瑞迪斯·罗吉.
This is Marge Sherwood.Meredith Logue.
你好吗?
How do you do ?
来和我们坐一起吧?我们正在等个朋友.
Do join us, won’t you ?We’re just waiting for a friend.
我...不了, 其实.我想这有些...
I...I won't, actually.
I think there's...
- 我们昨天在歌剧院见过对吗?  - 嗯...
- Did we see you at the opera last night ? - Uh...
你们是在等迪克?
Are you waiting for Dickie ?
迪克? 你...你...你认识迪克?
Dickie ? Do you...Do you...Do you know Dickie ?
你是在歌剧院.噢, 难怪...是的, 我在那儿.
You were at the opera.Oh, that explains...Yes, I was there.
我和迪克一起去的.
I was there with Dickie.
我就知道.
[ Exhales ]I knew it.
我告诉过你.
I told you.
玛吉, 我和你不熟,所以我也没权利对你说什么...
Marge, I don't know you,so I've got no right to...
迪克爱你.他就是...这样说吧...
Dickie loves you.He's...Well...
我想你会发现他现正赶着去找你呢.
I think you’ll find he's on his way home to you.
好吧, 你是怎么..怎么..怎么知道这些的?
[ Sighs ] Well, how..how..how would you know that ?
他... 告诉了我一切.
He... told me everything.
噢不, 我本应该在15分钟前和他见面的,那么, 嗯,
No, I was supposed to meet him 15 minutes ago, so, uh,
我想我得走了.
I'm gonna go now,I think.
天, 除非他是计划好了要让我们见面.
God, unless he meant us to meet.
那就有点太残酷了,不是吗?
That’d be a little cruel,wouldn't it ?
不, 不是, 我们在等其它朋友.
No, no, we're meeting another friend.
- 汤姆·瑞普雷.   - 你认识过汤姆·瑞普雷?
- Tom Ripley.   - Do you know Tom Ripley ?
不, 不认识. 我当然听说过他,不过还没见过面, 没见过.
No, no. I've heard about him,of course, but I didn't meet him, no.
- 我不要了. 不要了, 谢谢.
- [Italian]- Not for me. No, grazie.
希望我没把事情搞复杂了.
Hope I didn't complicate matters.
天, 没什么,没发生过任何过分的事.
God, nothing, nothing...untoward happened.
没有, 没有任何事能阻止他回到你身边,
No, there is nothing to prevent you from welcoming him back,
能阻止他和你结婚.
from marrying him.
再见.我很高兴又认识了一位新朋友.
Good-bye.I'm happy to put a face to a name.
再见, 彼得.别，请别站起来.
Good-bye, Peter.Please, don't get up.
现在我完全不知所措了.你觉得他会回来吗?
[ Marge ] Now I don't know what to think. Do you think he's coming back ?
对不起. 对不起.得更新我的档案.
Sorry. Sorry.Had to renew my papers.
他们总能把只要盖一个章就能解决的事搞得很复杂。
Never one stamp when they can make you line up for three.
- 你们等了很久吗?   - 没有.
- Have you been waiting long ? - Not at all.
- 早上好, 汤姆.   - 早上好. 对不起.
- Morning, Tom.   - Hi. Sorry.
你还好吗? 你看上去像撞了鬼一样.
You okay ? You look like you’ve seen a ghost.
迪克昨天晚上也在歌剧院.
Dickie was at the opera last night.
我不信. 呃...野马也不能把他拽到那儿去...
I don't believe that. Uh...Wild horses couldn't drag Dickie...
他和其它人一起去的, 你知道,
[ Laughs ] Well, he was there with someone, you know,
我想她一定是硬拉他去的.
so I suppose she must have dragged him.
这不公平.
It's not fair.
我想我得回蒙吉了.迪克应该是已经回家了.
I think I'm going back to Mongi.I think Dickie's coming home.
是吗? 我...那简直是太好.
Really ? I...Well,that’s just swell.
不, 你知道, 你总是比我先知. 太好了.
No, you know, you'reway ahead of me. Great.
我听到那席话时还觉得挺感动...对不起.
That was rather moving when I heard...I'm sorry.
梅瑞迪斯是我昨晚在歌剧院看到的那个美国女孩.
Meredith is the American girl I saw at the opera last night.
- 她了解迪克一些事.   - 哦, 上帝啊.
- She’s been seeing something of Dickie. - Oh, my God.
但是重点在于,迪克...我们都知道.
But the point is,Dickie...and we all know this.
迪克爱玛吉.他也很想念她.
Dickie loves Marge.And he misses her.
我有一种负疚感.玛吉并不了解,
I feel guilty.Marge doesn't understand this,
但是每当迪克做错了事，我都会感觉愧疚.
but whenever Dickie does something, I feel guilty.
好像是心有灵犀一样.
[ Chuckles ]As if that makes sense.
[ Italian ]
[Choir Singing in Italian]
[Ends]
[Knocking At Door]
- [Knocking]
- [Piano: Stops]
迪克.
[Freddie]Dickie.
- 迪克, 开门. 是我.
- [Knocking]- Dickie, come on. It's me.
费雷迪.让我进来.
It's Freddie.Let me in.
迪克.
Dickie.
你好, 费雷迪.是汤姆.
Hello, Freddie.It's Tom.
嗯, 迪克在哪儿?
Um, where's Dickie ?
你好吗?
How are you ?
还不错. 呃, 是的, 谢谢.他出门了. 他去吃晚饭了.
I'm good. Uh, yes, thank you.He's gone. He went to dinner.
- 他在澳泰罗饭店. 你知道澳泰罗吗?   - 不, 不, 不.
- He's at Otello's. You know Otello's ?- No, no, no.
我..我不认为他会在下午6:30用晚餐.
I..I don't think he's at dinner at 6:30 P.M.
如果你说他还吃午饭,也许我会相信你.
If you said he was still at lunch, maybe I'd believe you.
你知道吗?难以置信.
You know ? [ Laughs ]Incredible.
我是说,那家伙就这么，你知道，就这么一下子从地球上消失了.
I mean, the guy just, you know,disappeared off the face of the earth.
我想是吧.
I guess.
房东,就我所知...
The landlady,as far as I could tell...
房东说他现在就在这儿.
The landlady said he was here right now.
你搜吧.
Search the place.
我..我只是不明白...不明白迪克为什么要躲着你.
I..I just don't... I don't know why you'd imagine that Dickie would hide from you.
因为他以前也躲过我.
Because he's been hiding from me.
- 圣诞节怎么搞的?  - 圣诞节怎么了?
- What happened at Christmas ?  - What about Christmas ?
他本该一起来滑雪的.我连个电报都没收到...
He was supposed to come skiing.I didn't get a cable...
或是一个电话，一张便条，或是一个...
or a call or a little note or a...
- 老实说, 连个屁都没有.
- [ Grunts ] - Frankly, a fart.
他最近很沉迷于他的音乐.
Well, he's been very involved with his music.
嗯,我认为他的理论.. 是...
Um, I think his theory... is...
你先得把自己裹在茧里,呃,才能变成一只蝴蝶.
that you have to go into a cocoon,uh, before you can be a butterfly.
胡说八道.
Which is horseshit.[ Mutters ]
你听过他吹这个?呃,他不会.
You hear him play this thing ?Well, he can't.
你是怎么找到他的?
How did you find him ?
这是这么偏远的一所房子.要我给你倒杯酒吗?
It's such an out-of-the-way apartment.Can I fixyou a drink ?
不, 谢谢了.美国快递.
No, thanks.At the American Express.
[ Strikes Random Keys ]
开玩笑的.
Some kid.[ Strikes Keys ]
你住这儿吗?
Are you living here ?
不, 不. 我只在这儿逗留几天.
No, no. I'm staying here for a few days.
-那...
- But...- [Strikes Keys]
这是台新钢琴.也许不该在这儿...
It's a new piano.Probably shouldn't...
[ Striking Keys ]
- 也许不该...
- Probably shouldn't...- [Strikes Keys]
这地方装修过?
Did this place come furnished ?
看起来完全不像迪克的风格, 呃...
It doesn't look like Dickie's, uh...
太差劲了,不是吗?
It's really horrible,isn't it ?
太, 呃, 太小资了.
It's so, uh, bourgeois.
噢, 那是一个, 呃...你得..小心点.
Oh, that's a, uh...You should..Watch that.
不好意思...让我来.
Excuse...Excuse me.
我来.
Excuse me.
事实上, 唯一一样像迪克的...是你.
In fact, the only thing that looks like Dickie... is you.
- 不太像吧.  - 嗯.
- Hardly.  - Hmm.
你做过头发?
Have you done something to your hair ?
你想说什么，弗雷迪?
Is there something you'd like to say, Freddie ?
- 什么?   - 你想说什么?
- What ?  - You have something you'd like to say ?
我想我正说着.
I think I'm saying it.
有些事不对劲.
Something’s going on.
要么就是他改变了信仰,
Either he's converted to Christianity,
要么就是发生了其它什么事.
or there's something else.
呃, 我建议你还是自己去找迪克问清楚.
Well, I would suggest you ask Dickie that yourself.
澳泰罗餐馆就在街道出去的路口处.
Otello's is on della Croce just off the Corso.
就在街道出去的路口处?
Is it on della Croce just off the Corso ?
是呀. 你学得可真快，不是吗?
Sure. You're a quick study, aren’t you ?
上次你连意大利语的手肘和屁股都分不清楚.
Last time you didn't know you ass from your elbow.
现在你已经能为我指路了.
Now you're giving me directions.
这不公平. 你也许能分得清你的屁股和手肘.
That’s not fair. You probably do know your ass from your elbow.
我们会再见面的.
I'll see you.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[ Italian ]
不是迪克·格林立夫. 托马斯·瑞普雷.
[Freddie]No Dickie Greenleaf. Thomas Ripley.
是.
Si.[Italian]
你好, 迪克.
Ciao, Dickie.
迪克不弹钢琴.
Dickie doesn't play the piano.
汤米.
[Freddie]Tommy.
汤米!
Tommy!
[Freddie Groaning]
[Tom Grunting]
[Man And Woman Chattering]
噢!你可真逗.
Oh ! [ Laughs ]You're making me laugh.
不. 你不过是喝多了.噢. 你不过是...
No. You’re just so drunk.Oh. You’re just...
你还能怎么样呢，嗯?你该看看我其它的朋友都醉成什么样了.
What can you do, eh ?You should see my other friends.
- 你还能做什么呢?
- What canyon do ?- [ Italian ]
是呀.根本就是一头猪.
Yes.Such a pig.
- [ Laughs ]
- [ Italian ]
嗨, 如果我这就算醉了的话,想想他老公会怎么说.
[ Imitating Freddie ] Hey, if I'm drunk,think what her husband's saying.
- 打搅了.   - 迪克.格林立夫?
- La polizia. - Dickie Greenleaf?
- 是的.   - 罗维利尼警探.
- Yes.   - Inspector Roverini.
- 我们能进来吗?   - 请吧.
- Can we come in ? - Please.
这真是令人震惊，不是吗?
It's a terrible shock,huh ?
迈尔斯先生昨天是几点钟走的?
W-What time did Signor Miles leave yesterday ?
噢, 嗯, 我不敢肯定. 我想是...
Oh, um, I can't be certain exactly. I...
8:00, 9:00.
[ Italian ]
我们都, 呃,喝了太多酒.
We'd both taken on, uh,far too many drinks.
不过那时天已经很黑了，天当然已经很黑了，当我..当我搀他进他自己的车里.
But it was dark. It was certainly dark when I.. when I walked him to his car.
那么他开车走了,那么,呃,你做了什么?
So he drove away,and, uh, you did what ?
- 上床睡觉.
- I went to bed.- [ Italian ]
弗雷迪很能喝，不过我才喝了两杯就不行了.
Freddie's a big man, but I'm in trouble after a couple of drinks.
我一直都很难受...
I've been suffering all...
谁找到他的?
Who found him ?
请你理解,我一定得请你..
[ Italian ]You understand, I must ask you...
留在罗马,格林立夫先生.
to stay in Rome,Signor Greenleaf.
好的,如果能有所帮助的话,当然.
Yes, if it's gonna help,certainly.
那么, 法医, 他得, 嗯...
So, the doctor, he has to make the, um...
- [ Italian ]
- 验尸.  - 对, 就是这样.
- Postmortem. - Yeah, exactly.
但是,你看,他的初步推论是...
But, you know,his first conclusion...
迈尔斯先生是昨晚7：00以前被杀害的.
was that Signor Miles was killed not later than 7:00 yesterday evening.
呃, 他在开车走之前当然不会已经死了.
Well, he certainly wasn't dead when he drove away in his car.
不会.
No.
[ Chattering ]
[ Italian ]
没事.
[ Italian ]It's okay.
- 真没事?   - 是, 是的.
- Okay ?   - Si, si.
- 是他杀的弗雷迪?   - 玛吉.你什么时候来的?
- Did he kill Freddie ?  - Marge. When did you get here ?
告诉我真相.是他杀的弗雷迪吗?
Tell me the truth.Did he kill Freddie ?
我发誓他没有.他当然不会这么做.
I'd swear he didn't.Of course he didn't.
我又来碰碰运气.等在这儿, 看着他.
I tried again.Waiting here, watching for him.
相反, 是你.每次我找迪克，找到的都是你.
Instead, it's you.Whenever I look for Dickie, I find you.
你脸怎么了?
What happened to your face ?
迪克...迪克干的.
Dickie...Dickie did it.
- 迪克?   - 我的脸. 我们起了些争执.
- Dickie ? - My face. There was an argument.
我...我说了些,我不该说的，而我...
I...I said some things I shouldn't have said and I...
是关于你.关于他如此恶劣地对待你, 对待我们每一个人.
About you. About the appalling way he's treating you, all of us.
接下来我就发现他只朝我冲过来.
And the next thing I know,he's launched himself at me.
- 你上来吗?  - 什么?
- Are you getting on ? - What ?
上来.我带你去见他.
Get on.I'll take you to him.
[ Italian ]
[ Engine Stops ]
- 他住哪儿?  - 在前面，我们过了几个街区.
- Where does he live ? - We passed it a few blocks back.
那有警察.在乔亚的宅第.
It's where the police were.The Palazzo Gioia.
看, 他们甚至不知道我在罗马,我不能牵累迪克.
Look, they don't even know I'm in Rome,and I'm not gonna incriminate Dickie.
恩, 也许我该走了.
Well, perhaps I shouldn't go either.
不. 好吧,你想走就走吧,但是别对警官说看到过我.
No. Well, go if you want to, but just don't talk to the police about my face.
如果他们知道他打了我和他的火爆脾气,那他就能攻击弗雷迪.
If they know he hit me and his temper,then he could've hit Freddie.
呆会见.
I'll catch up with you later.
[ Engine Starts ]
格林立夫先生!
[ Italian ]Signor Greenleaf !
是格林立夫先生!快，快!
It's Signor Greenleaf !Presto, presto !
[ Shouting in Italian ]
开门!
Open the door !
快开门!
Open up !
-我住这儿!
- [ Italian ]- I live here !
格林立夫先生!
Mr. Greenleaf !
我们能上去吗?你不介意吧?
Can we go up ?Do you mind ?
当然.你脸怎么了?
Of course.What happened to your face ?
我的电单车. 在被摄影师追赶的时候摔的.
My scooter. I fell off getting chased by photographers.
电话, 媒体,我觉得..我觉得在被追捕.
The telephone, the press,I've been...I'm feeling hounded.
你就不能别泄漏我的地址吗?
Do you think you could not give out my address ?
从未.有很多人要求，但我们都拒绝了,连你的未婚妻都没有告知.
Never.We've had many requests, and we say no, even to your fiancée.
我真的不想见任何人.
I really don't want to see anybody.
- 包括你的未婚妻?   - 包括她.
- Even your fiancée ?  - Even her.
[Man Speaking Italian]
- 那汤姆·瑞普雷呢?  - 汤姆·瑞普雷怎么了?
- What about Thomas Ripley ? - What about Tom Ripley ?
你和瑞普雷先生一起去了圣雷默.对吗?
You and Signor Ripley went to San Remo.Is that right ?
是的, 我们..我们去了圣雷默.那已经是几个月以前的事情了.
Yes, we..We went to San Remo.That was months ago.
十一月, 我想是.是吗?
November, I thought.Was it ?
- 你和汤姆说过吗?   - 十一月七日我记得.
- Did you speak to Tom ? - November 7 is my information.
我记不清确切日期了.
I don't remember the exact date.
- 你上一次见到瑞普雷先生是什么时候?  - 几天前。
- When did you last see Signor Ripley ? - A few days ago.
- 他住你这儿吗?   - 没有.
- Does he stay with you here ?  - No.
没有.
No.
大致是这样的.两天前,
Here is a pattern.Two days ago,
弗雷迪·迈尔斯死了,嗯?
Freddie Miles is dead,hmm ?
他离开你的公寓,
He leaves your apartment,
就被谋杀了.
and he's murdered.
昨天, 一条盛满石块的小船在圣雷默被发现.
Yesterday, a little boat is found in San Remo full of rocks.
船主告诉警局船是11月7日被盗的.
And the owner tells the police it was stolen on November 7.
我们看了旅店纪录...
We look at hotel records...
我们发现...
and we see...
迪克·格林立夫在圣雷默.
Dickie Greenleaf is staying in San Remo.
船主记得是两个美国人租的船.
And then our boatman remembers two Americans taking a boat.
这不是大概.纯属巧合.
That is not a pattern.That's a coincidence.
在圣雷默有50家旅馆.
There must be 50 hotels in San Remo.
那天也许有100个人租了船.
There were probably a hundred people renting a boat that day.
31人.
Thirty-one people.
31人,是的.
Thirty-one, yeah.
[ Italian ]
- 玛吉·舍伍德.  - 这次是舍伍德小姐.
- Marge Sherwood.  - That is Miss Sherwood now.
让她进来.
Let her in.
让她进来.这又有能怎么样? 让她进来.
Let her in.What's the difference ? Let her in.
不! 事实上...事实上, 不.
No ! Actually...Actually, no.
我会...我会很感激的...
I would...I would really appreciate it...
如果你等会再让舍伍德小姐进来的话.
if you would ask Miss Sherwood to come back later.
[ Italian ]
谢谢.
Thank you.
我可以问一下吗..
May I ask you..
为什么你宁可对朋友说，却不愿对你的未婚妻说?
Why would you speak to your friend and not your fiancée ?
呃, 我..我想我刚才已经说过了.
Well,I..I think I just said.
嗯, 瑞普雷先生在帮我处理一些事务.
Um, Mr. Ripley was handling some business for me.
不是瑞普雷先生想嫁给我...
Nor does Mr. Ripley want to marry me...
并且每日每夜缠着你，问你什么时候结婚.
and ask me every single day if I'll marry him and when.
你有瑞普雷先生的照片吗?
Do you keep a photograph of Signor Ripley ?
我没有随身携带男性朋友照片的习惯.
I'm not in the habit of carrying around photographs of my male friends.
我想我是让你困扰了.
Now I think I've upset you.
对不起. 我的英语,可能,太差了.
Sorry. My English,perhaps, is coarse.
是有点差,是的.
It is a little coarse,yes.
我道歉.
I'm sorry.
但是你..没有人在圣雷默后见到过汤姆·瑞普雷.
But you..No one has seen Signor Ripley since San Remo.
- 我见过.   - 你见过, 是啊.
- I have.   - You have, yes.
舍伍德小姐也见过他.问问她. 还有, 嗯,
And so has Miss Sherwood.Ask her. And, um,
让我想想他当时住在哪家旅馆...
if I can remember the name of the hotel he was staying at...
嗯,高多尼旅馆.汤姆住在高多尼.
Um, the Goldoni.Tom was staying at the Goldoni.
高多尼.高多尼.很好,很好,但是...
Goldoni. The Goldoni.Good, good, but...
是的,你是对的.
Yes, you are right.
你是对的.纯属巧合.
You are right.A coincidence.
[Siren Wailing, Distant]
我期待下一次见面.
[ Sighing ] I look forward to our next meeting.
嗯? 那时我会更注重我的英文的.
Hmm ? When I will be more careful with my English.
呃.我有证人说当时看到两个男人...
[Roverini] Ah. I have a witness who thinks they saw two men...
进了迈尔斯先生的车.
getting into Mr. Miles' car.
她想来正面指证一下.
And she wants to identify you in a confronto.
一组人.明天,怎么样?
Lineup. Tomorrow, then ?
呃,明天.
Uh, tomorrow.
[ Chuckles ]
- 早上好,舍伍德小姐.   - 早上好.
- Buon giorno, Miss Sherwood. - Buon giorno.
他在里面,不过我认为他现在真不想见任何人.
He's in, but I really don't think he wants to meet anybody.
[Knocking]
迪克?
Dick ?
Dickie ?
我知道你能听到我.
I know you can hear me.
[ Sighing ]
我想说我会数到三,如果你不开门的话...
I was gonna say that I would count to three, and if you didn't open the door...
我就不会再……
But I won't count anymore.
指望你了.
On you.
我不会再指望你了.
I won't count on you anymore.
不管你做了什么没做什么,
Whatever it is you've done or haven't done,
你已经伤透了我的心.
you've broken my heart.
这是我指认你的一项罪行.
That's one thing I know you're guilty of.
我不明白是为了什么.
And I don't know why.[ Sobbing ]
我不明白是为了什么.我就是不明白是为了什么.
I don't know why.I just don't know why.
[Footsteps Receding]
[Typewriter Keys Clattering]
[Thunder Rumbling]
我亲爱的汤姆.
[Tom's Voice]My dear Tom.
我再也无法忍受了.
I’m getting out of this.
弗雷迪的死，希尔维那的死.
Freddie's death. Silvana.
我曾经想过要去自首，但我不能.
I’ve thought about going to the police,but I can’t do it.
我无法再面对这一切了.
I can’t face it.
我再也无法面对这一切了.
I can’t face anything anymore.
我再也无法面对更多了.
我希望我能将我的生命交给你.
I wish I could give you the life I took for granted.
[Typewriter Bell Dings,Clattering Continues]
你总是能猜透我心里在想什么, 汤姆.
You've always understood what's at the heart of me, Tom.
玛吉永远都不能.
Marge never could.
我想这就是为什么我给你写这封信的原因,
I suppose that's why I'm writing this to you,
你是我唯一的兄弟.
the brother I never had.
也是我唯一真正的朋友.
The only true friend I ever had.
从各方面来看,
in all kinds of ways,
你都更像是我父亲更想要的儿子.
you're much more like the son my father wanted.
你知道你能改变人,
I realize you can change the people,
改变风景,
change the scenery,
但却永远改变不了自己已经腐败的内心.
but you can't change your own rotten self.
现在我完全失去了方向.
Now I can't think what to do or where to go.
我被一切不可挽回的错事所困扰.
I’m haunted by everything I’ve done and can’t undo.
对不起.
I’m sorry.
我把迪克·格林立夫的生活搞得一团糟，不是吗?
I've made a mess of being Dickie Greenleaf, haven't I ?
汤姆!
Tom !
我在那儿见你!
I'll see you over there !
[Bell Tolling]
真不好意思让你经历这些, 彼得.
I'm so sorry to put you through this, Peter.
我只是无法在意大利语这么烂的情况下一个人去面对警方.
I just can't face going to the police by myself when my Italian's so rotten.
别傻了.没事的.
Don't be so daft.It's fine.
我很高兴你最终还是到了威尼斯.
I'm delighted you finally made it to Venice.
我很开心,和谣言相反,你还好好的毫发无伤.
I'm delighted, contrary to rumor,that you're still in one piece.
- 什么谣言?   - 哦,你知道.
- What rumor ? - Oh, you know.
迪克谋杀了你，并冒用你的护照到处旅行.
That Dickie murdered you and is traveling under your passport.
我知道.这是很荒谬.
I know. It's ridiculous.
[Man Shouting in Italian]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[Phone Ringing]
欢迎来威尼斯.
Welcome to Venice.
天啊,这地方很臭,不是吗?你闻到了吗?
God, this place reeks, doesn't it ?Can you smell it ?
不管怎样, 我不能再推迟了.
Anyway, I've got to the bottom of the delay, finally.
我们在等从罗马来的警探.
We're waiting for someone from Rome.
你说什么?他们从罗马派了人来?
What do you mean ?They've sent for someone from Rome ?
- 呃,是的.这挺好,不是吗?  - 不,我以为...
- Well, yes. That's good, isn't it ? - No, I thought...
在意大利不是这么运作的,我以为各地区都是独立的.
that didn't happen in Italy,that each region is separate.
我肯定...我读过...
I was sure that..I've read that..
你也读过报纸.你知道这件事有多重大.
You've read the papers.You know what a big deal it's been.
- 美国游客被谋杀了.  - 但是,这件事能先搁一搁吗?
- American tourist murdered. - Actually, can we not do this now ?
- 这臭味真是..
- The stench really is..- [Man Speaking Italian]
[ Italian ]
[ Continues in Italian ]
他接管这个案子,是因为他们对前一任负责人很不满..
He's taken over the case, 'cause they're annoyed that the previous chap...
让弗雷德谋杀案唯一的嫌疑犯迪克,
let Dickie disappear when he was, um,
就这么失踪了.
the only suspect in Freddie’s murder.
[ Italian ]
在罗马，大约三周以前.
In Rome,about three weeks ago.
这句我能听懂.
I knew that one.
嗯..
Um..[ Italian ]
[ Italian ]
你是同性恋吗?有趣的不知所云.
Are you a homosexual ?
Interesting non sequitur.
不是.
No.
- 不是.  - 噢.
- No.    - Oh.
顺便说一下, 嗯,官方是没有意大利同性恋这种讲法的.
By the way, um, officially there are no Italian homosexuals.
这让米开朗基罗和莱昂纳多很是困扰.
Makes Michelangelo and Leonardo very inconvenient.
嗯?
Eh ?
告诉他...我有个未婚妻.
Tell him...I have a fiancée.
迪克也有个未婚妻.
And Dickie has a fiancée.
至于那个弗雷迪·迈尔斯,他没准有一打的未婚妻.
And that Freddie Miles probably had a string of them.
[ Italian ]
我的老天呀.
Mamma mia.[ Italian ]
- [Inspector Laughing]
- [ Chuckling ]
- 他说了什么?   - 他说"这么多未婚妻."
- What did he say ?  - He says "so many fiancées."
[ Italian ]
他问...是不是你杀了弗雷迪·迈尔斯...
He’s asking... if you killed Freddie Miles...
然后又杀了迪克·格林立夫.
and then killed Dickie Greenleaf.
不! 没有,我没有杀弗雷迪·迈尔斯,更没有杀迪克·格林立夫.
No ! No, I did not kill Freddie Miles and then kill Dickie Greenleaf.
他是在指控我吗?问问他他是否在指控我.
Is he accusing me ?Ask him if he's accusingme.
这里的办事程序就是这样,这总比严刑逼供好多了.
The way it works here,it's better to be less volatile.
-但这也太荒谬了!
- But it’s absurd!- [ Italian ]
[ Italian ]
他们在迪克罗马的寓所里发现了这个.
They found this in Dickie's place in Rome.
-你打开过?   -当然.
- You opened this ?  - Of course.
这是一封遗书.
It's a suicide note.
你早就看过这份遗书,还问我这些问题?
You asked me all these questions and you already read this suicide note ?
我不相信那封遗书.你呢?
I don't believe that letter.Do you ?
迪克的信.你相信吗?
Dickie's letter.Do you believe it ?
我不知道什么该相信.
I don't know what to believe.
那你能想象吗，如果是他杀了弗雷迪，那会是怎样一个情形？
Can you imagine, though, if he did kill Freddie, what that must be like ?
每天早上照常醒来.我是说,你怎么能做到?
Just to wake up every morning.I mean, how can you ?
醒来像个常人一样的生活?喝你的咖啡.
Just wake up and be a person ?Drink your coffee.
呃,不管你做了什么，不管有过可怕，不管有多痛苦,
Well, whatever you do,however terrible, however hurtful,
它都是有意义的,不是吗,在你的头脑里.
it all makes sense,doesn't it, in your head.
你从未遇到过自认为是坏人的人.
You never meet anybody who thinks they're a bad person.
没有, 我知道,但是你仍然饱受煎熬.你一定会这样.你杀了人.
No, I know, but you're still tormented.You must be. You've killed someone.
你不会将过去放进地下室的房间里吗？
Don't you just take the past and put it in a room in the basement,
锁上门，再也不走进去?
and lock the door and never go in there ?
-那是我会做的.   -上帝啊,是这样.
- That's what I do. - God, yes.
不过,当然,按我的情况,可能需要一整幢楼来装我的记忆.
But, of course, in my case,it's probably a whole building.
-然后你遇到一个对你而言特别的人,
-  [ Piano: Stops ]- And then you meet someone special,
你想做的只是扔给他们这把钥匙.
and all you want to do is toss them the key.
说 "开了.进来吧."
Say "Open up. Step inside."
但是你不能...
But you can't...
-因为里面很黑...
- [Resumes]- because it's dark...
还有恶魔.
and there are demons.
一旦有人看见里面有多肮脏...
And if anybody saw how ugly it is...
现在是音乐在影响你的情绪
Now that's the music talking.
如果你是在弹“站起来，布朗妈妈”想忧郁也难了
It's harder to be bleak if you're playing "Knees Up, Mother Brown."
我一直都想……
I keep wanting to do that.
冲开门...
Fling...the door open.
[Resumes]
让阳光洒进来，把一切都清洗干净.
Just let the light in,clean everything out.
如果我有一块巨大的橡皮,能擦除一切
If I could take a giant eraser and rub out everything,
从我自己开始...
starting with myself...
问题在于,彼得,如果...
The thing is, Peter, if...
- 嗯?   - 如果...
- Hmm ?  - If...
如果...
If...
如果没有钥匙,对吗?
No key, huh ?
[Boy Singing in Latin]
[ Continues ]
-玛吉.   -彼得.
- Marge.  - Peter.
-很高兴见到你.  -你好，玛吉.
- So good to see you.  - Hello, Marge.
汤姆.
Tom.
-我发现你找到了彼得.  -我想是我们彼此找到了对方.
- I see you found Peter. - I think we sort of found each other.
-迪克的父亲在哪儿?  -他今天早上才能到.
- Where's Dickie's father ? - He's not coming till the morning.
他的胃.我觉得这儿的食物不适合他.
Evidently his stomach. I don't think the food here is agreeing with him.
哦,我很期待见到他.
Oh, I was looking forward to seeing him.
迪克没有自杀.我确信.
Dickie hasn't killed himself.I'm sure of that.
现在有一位私人侦探正着手调查此案.
There's a private detective on the case now.
麦卡伦先生，迪克的父亲雇来的.
A Mr. MacCarron Dickie's father's employed.
- 这太好了.  - 他是个美国人.
- That's a terrific idea. - He's American.
他已经查出迪克在失踪前一天...
He's already discovered that Dickie cashed checks for $1 ,000...
刚取了1000美元.
the day before he disappeared.
小姐.
[ Man ]Signora.
你在跳进台伯河前会这样做吗?
Is that what you do before you jump into the Tiber ?
我不这么认为.
I don’t think so.
-这是你的?   -不，这是汤姆的.
- Is this you ? - No, it's Tom's.
很不错，不是吗?
Splendid, eh ?
天啊.谁付的房租?
Golly.Who's paying for this ?
彼得替我找的.
Peter found it for me.
我能付的起是因为这里又潮湿...又破旧.
I can afford it because it's damp and... falling down.
-汤姆改造过这房子.   -太棒了.
- Tom's transformed it. - This is spectacular.
这就是为什么汤姆希望你能住下来.
That's why Tom wanted you to stay.
这总比挤在我的小屋里好.
It's better than trying to squeeze into my room.
我知道你讨厌旅馆.
And I know how you hate hotels.
旅馆就可以了.
A hotel would have been fine.
我们得告诉格林立夫先生.他的佣金已经用到哪儿了.
We'll have to tell Mr. Greenleaf how far his dollar stretched.
-什么这么可笑?
- [ Chuckles ]- What's funny ?
我只是想起汤姆第一次来蒙吉.
I was just thinking about when Tom first came to Mongibello.
-再看看你现在.   -看我什么?
- And look at you now. - Look at me what ?
贵族出生.
To the manor born.
[Bell Tolling]
格林立夫先生?
[Tom]Mr. Greenleaf?
[Continues]
格林立夫先生?
Mr. Greenleaf?
汤姆.你好吗?你看起来真不错.
Tom. How are you ?You look well.
-谢谢你,先生，我还不错.  -和在纽约时判若两人啊.
- Thank you, sir. I am well. - Far cry from New York.
-是啊.   -玛吉.
- Yes, it is.  - Marge.
早上好.不寻常的天气.
Good morning.Unusual weather.
-是呀.  -你呢,先生.好点了吗?
- Very. - And you, sir. Any better ?
很好.用热水捂着.
Pretty good.Sticking with hot water.
-麦卡隆先生呢?  -在圣雷默.
- Where's Mr. MacCarron ?- San Remo.
警察都是业余的.
The police are amateurs.
呃,我的孩子,不错的转变,不是吗?
Well, my boy, it's come to a pretty pass, hasn't it ?
侦探在圣雷默找什么?
What is the detective hoping to find in San Remo ?
他在进行地毯式的搜索.我正在了解我的儿子,汤姆.
He's being thorough.I'm learning about my son, Tom.
现在他失踪了,我了解到很多关于他的事,
Now he's missing,I'm learning a great deal about him,
我希望你能帮我填上一些空白.
and I hope that you can fill in some more blanks for me.
玛吉已经将蒙吉那部分填得差不多了.
Marge has been good enough to do that about Mongibello.
我会尽最大努力的,先生.很明显,我会为迪克做一切事情.
I'll try my best, sir. Obviously,I'll do anything to help Dickie.
-很好.这个理论,
-[Continues]- Good. This theory,
他留给你的那封信.
the letter he left for you.
警察认为这清楚地指出了...
The police think that's a clear indication...
他打算对自己,呃,做些事情.
he was planning on doing something,uh, to himself.
我不相信.
I just don't believe that.
亲爱的,你只是不愿去相信.
You don't want to, dear.
我想和汤姆单独谈谈.
I'd like to talk to Tom alone.
也许就这个下午.你觉得呢?
Perhaps this afternoon.Would you mind?
玛吉,一个男人对他的爱人所说的...
Marge, what a man may say to his sweetheart...
和对他的朋友所说的（是不一样的）...
and what he'll admit to another fellow...
比如说?
Such as ?
[Continues]
真是在浪费生命和机遇.
[ Clears Throat ]What a waste of lives and opportunities.
我宁可付100美元给那个萨克斯手让他闭嘴!
I'd pay that fellow a hundred dollars right now to shut up !
不,玛吉连一半都不知道.
No, Marge doesn't know the half of it.
还有他的护照照片.
And his passport photo.
你听说了吗？把他自己的脸划成那个样子?
Did you hear ? To scratch out his own face like that ?
你能想象吗?
Can you imagine ?
他一定要这样钻牛角尖吗?
Frame of mind you'd have to be in ?
"我想过要去自首,但是我不能.
"I've thought about going to the police,but I can't face it.
我再也忍受不了了."
I can't face anything anymore."
我觉得愧疚.我觉得是我把他推开了.
I feel guilty. I feel like I pushed him away.
我觉得每当我开口劝阻,他听到的都是你的声音.
I feel like I spoke and he heard you.
嗯,
Well,[ Clears Throat ]
与其说是我们把他推开了,还不如说是他把我们都推开了吧?
if we all pushed him away,what about him pushing us away ?
你曾经是我儿子最好的朋友.
You've been a great friend to my son.
每件事都是别人的错.
Everything is someone else's fault.
我们都想让他放任自流,
We all want to sow wild oats,
但是总有人得...得...
but somebody's got to...got to...
怎么说来着?
What is the word ?
你知道,当有人和他对峙的时候,
You know, the moment someone confronts him,
他总是痛殴对方.
he lashes out.
他总是这样.
He always has.
你知道, 人们总是说你不能选择你的父母,
You know, people always say that you can't choose your parents,
但是你也不能选择你的孩子.
but you can't choose your children.
迪克.
- [Knocking]- [Freddie's Voice] Dickie.
你就像个吸血水蛭.你很令人厌烦.
[Dickie's Voice] You can be a leech. You can be quite boring.
-住手!    -令人厌烦.
- [Tom's Voice] Stop it ! - [Dickie's Voice] It's boring.
- [Knocking]
- [ Voices Overlapping, indistinct]
住手,住手,住手!
[Tom Screaming]Stop, stop, stop !
-住手,住手,住手!   - 汤米,汤米.
- Stop, stop, stop ! - [Freddie's Voice] Tommy, Tommy.
像个小姑娘.
[Dickie's Voice]Like a little girl.
- Like a little girl.- [Knocking]
[Knocking]
来了.
- [Knocking]- Coming.
- 不好意思.我睡着了.   - 总算开了.
- Sorry. I was asleep. - Finally.
-我一定是睡着了.   -迪克的爸爸走了吗?
- I must have fallen asleep. - Did Dickie's dad go ?
你看起来气色很差,汤姆.是发噩梦了吗?
You look ghastly, Tom.Did you have a nightmare ?
-他时差还没调过来.  -噢,可怜的老人.
- He's having an early night. - Oh, poor man.
你知道,我们会无休无止地敲下去.
You know, we were banging on that door forever.
噢-不.
[Marge]Uh-oh.
-我想我弄断了一根吊带.   -别介意.
- I think I've broken a strap. - Not guilty.
-我来弄点喝的.
- I'll fix some drinks.- [ Marge Giggling ]
噢!这就是在威尼斯步行.
Ah !You walk in Venice.
你还好吗?
Are you okay ?
我很好.
I'm fine.
-你想让我留下吗?   -不用了,没关系.
- Did you want me to stick around ? - No, it's okay.
我会回来的.
I could come back.
你的钥匙.
Your key.
-汤姆?
- [Knocking At Door]- [Marge] Tom ?
玛吉,我在洗澡.不需要太久的.
Marge, I'm in the bath.I won't be long.
汤姆,我必须同你谈谈.非常紧急.
Tom, I have to speak to you.It’s urgent.
来了.
Coming.
-我找到了迪克的戒指.  -什么?
- I found Dickie's rings. - What ?
你拿了迪克的戒指.
You have Dickie's rings.
这点我可以解释.
I can explain.
迪克向我保证过他决不会摘掉这个戒指.
Dickie promised me he would never take off this ring.
先让我穿上点衣服再来讨论此事.
Let me put some clothes on and we'll talk about this.
- 我必须告诉格林立夫先生.  - 玛吉,你太过敏了.
- I have to tell Mr. Greenleaf. - Marge, you're being hysterical.
他向我保证过, "我发誓,我绝不会摘掉这个戒指直到我们结..."
He promised me, "I swear, I will never take off this ring until we get..."
-闭嘴!
- Shut up !- [ Gasping ]
我湿透了,玛吉.我的毛巾也掉了.
I'm wet, Marge.I've lost my towel.
我真的得穿上些衣服.
And I’d really like to put some clothes on.
去给我们俩倒杯酒好吗.
Go and pour us both a drink.
倒杯酒.
Pour us a drink.
玛吉?
Marge ?
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going ?
我没有乱翻.我只是...
I wasn't snooping.I just...
我只是想找针线缝一下我的文胸.
I was looking for a needle and thread to mend my bra.
你在用的这瓶香水.
That scent you're wearing.
是我买的.
I bought that for you.
关于迪克的一些事...
The thing about Dickie...
很多事.
So many things.
那天他从罗马回来晚了,
That day when he was late coming back from Rome,
我曾经尝试着告诉你.
I tried to tell you this.
他是和其它女孩好上了.我并不是指梅瑞迪斯.
He was with another girl.I'm not talking about Meredith, either.
另一个在酒吧里认识的女孩.
Another girl that we met in a bar.
他连五分钟的忠诚都保证不了.
He couldn't be faithful for five minutes.
所以当他作其它一些保证的时候,
So when he makes a promise,
并不像你我许诺一样...
it doesn't mean what it means when you make a promise...
会信守到底.
or I make a promise.
他有那么多的现实,迪克,而他又全部相信.
He has so many realities, Dickie,and he believes them all.
他撒谎.他撒谎.
He lies. He lies.
那还只是一半的情况,有时他甚至意识不到他在背叛誓言.
And that's his...Half the time he doesn't even realize he's doing it.
而今天,
And today,
我开始怀疑是否是他谋杀了弗雷迪.
I really started wondering whether he may have killed Freddie.
如果有人站出来和他对抗,他会变得如此疯狂.
He would get so crazy if anybody would contradict him.
是这样,你知道这一点.你知道这一点.
Well, you know that.You know that.
你知道这一点.
You know that.
这就是讽刺的地方,玛吉.
And that's the irony, Marge.
我爱你.
I loved you.
你也许已经知道,玛吉.我爱你.
You may as well know, Marge.I loved you.
我知道这时候说这个会很怪异,
I don't know, maybe it's grotesque of me to say this now,
所以...就请在一张纸或别的什么东西上...
so just... write it on apiece of paper or something...
写上"汤姆爱我,汤姆爱我"
and put it in your purse for a rainy day.
放到你的钱包里,将来也许可以作为慰籍.
"Tom loves me. Tom loves me."
-你为什么会有迪克的戒指    -我告诉过你.
- Why do you have Dickie's rings ?  - I told you.
-是他给我的.  -为什么?什么时候?
- He gave them to me.  - Why ? When ?
我觉得你刚才完全没有在听我对你说的话.
I feel as if you haven't been listening to anything I've been saying to you.
我不相信你.我不相信你.
I don't believe you.I don't believe you.
-这都是真的.    -你说的话...
- It's all true.  - I don't believe...
我一个字也不相信.
a single word you've said.[ Gasping, Shuddering ]
你在发抖,玛吉.看看你.
You're shivering, Marge.Look at you.
玛吉,我能抱着你吗?
Marge, can I hold you ?
你能让我抱着你吗?
Will you let me hold you ?
-玛吉?
- [ Screaming ]- Marge ?
-彼得!感谢上天你来了.   -怎么了?
- Peter ! Thank God you're here. - What’s going on ?
带我走.带我走.求求你了!
Get me out of here.Get me out of here. Please!
- 汤姆,你还好吗?
- [Peter] Tom, are you okay ?- [Marge Sobbing]
你试试.你试着劝劝她.
You try.You try talking to her.
-汤姆?   -我放弃.
- [Peter] Tom ? - I give up.
告诉我到底发生了什么.汤姆!
Tell me what's going on.Tom !
-我从未对她做过什么,我对她做过什么吗?  -听着...
- [Tom] What did I ever do to her? - Listen...
她能说出一件我曾经伤害过她的事吗?
Have her tell you one thing that I've ever done to her.
听着，你不能同她怄气.
You can't be angry with her.
她很迷惑,她需要一个迁怒的对象.
She's confused, and she needs someone to blame.
所以她迁怒于你.
So she blames you.
我会回去和她好好谈谈.
I'll go back home and talk to her.
至于你,
As for you,
要么换个安全剃刀,要么就留胡子吧.
either get a safety razor or grow a beard.
[Knocking]
-格林立夫先生在吗?-瑞普雷先生?
- Is Mr. Greenleaf here ?  - Mr. Ripley ?
-是我. -我是阿尔文·麦克隆.
- Yes. - I'm Alvin MacCarron.
我不知道,我不知道.我就知道是这样.
[Marge] I don't know,I don't know. I just know it.
玛吉,这只是女性的直觉，然而事实……
[Mr. Greenleaf] Marge, there's female intuition and then there are facts.
-汤姆.   -先生.
- Tom.   - Sir.
玛吉,你该等一等的.我没有...
Marge, you should have waited.I didn't...
彼得没有告诉你我会顺道去接你吗?
Didn't Peter say I'd come by and pick you up ?
玛吉在对我们说戒指的事情.
Marge has been telling us about the rings.
是啊,我也觉得很荒谬,我昨天并没有提起.
Yes, I feel ridiculous I didn't mention them yesterday.
我完全忘了.太荒谬了.
I clean forgot.Ridiculous.
也许只有一个理由能解释为什么你没有告诉我们.
Perhaps you didn't mention them because there's only one conclusion to be drawn.
我带玛吉去散散步.汤姆,麦克隆先生需要和你谈谈.
I'm going to take Marge for a walk.Tom, Mr. MacCarron needs to talk to you.
没必要吧.我们可以一起去酒吧.没这个必要.
There's no need. We could go to the bar. There's no need.
不,不.
No, no.
我认为你应该呆在这里.
I think you should stay here.
[Door Opening, Closing]
我能从这儿看到我的房间.
I could probably see my room from here.
我能看到我的房子.
I can see my house.
当你从远方眺望你的家时,感觉就像是在做梦,是不是?
When you see where you live from a distance, it's like a dream, isn't it ?
我没时间瞎扯
I don't care for B.S.
我不想听.也不想说.
I don't care to hear it.I don't care to speak it.
-好吧.   -你知道在普林斯顿的时候...
- Okay.  - Did you know that at Princeton...
迪克·格林立夫差点打死了一个男孩?
Dickie Greenleaf half-killed a boy ?
在一个聚会上为了些女孩争风吃醋.
At a party over some girl.
踹了那男孩的头好几脚,把他送进了医院.
Kicked the kid several times in the head, put him in the hospital.
男孩的下巴得用铁丝固定,丧失了部分听力.
Boy had a wire fixed in his jaw,lost some hearing.
你以为为什么迪克的父亲最初要把他送到欧洲来?
Why do you think Dickie's father sent him to Europe in the first place ?
罗马警局没想到来问格林立夫先生.
The Rome police didn't think to ask Mr. Greenleaf.
也没想过要去查查汤姆斯·瑞普雷是否真的...
Nor did they think to check on whether a Thomas Ripley...
曾经在普林斯顿上学.
had ever been a student at Princeton University.
噢,我发现汤姆·瑞普雷...
Oh, I turned up a Tom Ripley...
原来只是音乐系的一个钢琴调音师.
who had been a piano tuner in the music department.
你看,在美国,
You see, in America,
我们总是被教育要防患于未然.
we are taught to check a fact before it becomes a fact.
我们被训练去四处探听.
We're taught to nose around.
如果一个女孩溺水死了,
When a girl drowns herself,
查查看她是否怀孕了.
find out if that girl is pregnant.
查查看迪克是不是有什么不可告人的秘密.
Find out if Dickie had an embarrassment there.
格林立夫先生非常欣赏你的忠诚.他真的很欣赏.
Mr. Greenleaf appreciates your loyalty.He really does.
玛吉...她能有上百种推论.
Marge...She has a hundred theories.
有些事情是她不知道的.
There are a few things that she doesn't know.
我们希望她永远也不要知道.
We hope she never knows.
I hope she never knows.
三个不同的人...
Three different people...
看见迪克进了弗雷迪的车.
saw Dickie get into Freddie's car.
其中一个,并不会指认...
One man,who will not testify...
因为他当时是在和别人的妻子通奸,
because he was jumping somebody else's wife at the time,
他看到迪克从一辆红色跑车上取下牌照.
saw Dickie removing license plates from a red sports car.
警方之所以知道是因为这人本身就是个警察.
The police know about this man because he happens to be a policeman.
我在迪克的地下室里发现了这些.
I found these in the basement of Dickie's apartment.
它们是弗雷迪的车上的.
They belong to Freddie's car.
格林立夫先生叫我...
Mr. Greenleaf has asked me...
把这些扔到运河里去.
to lose these in the canal this evening.
[Bell Tolling]
格林立夫先生说他从迪克给你的信中...
Mr. Greenleaf feels that there was a silent promise...
觉察到了迪克对你的一些秘密承诺.
in Dickie's letter to you which he intends to honor.
他已经打算将迪克收入的一大部分...
He also intends to transfer a good portion...
转入你的账户.
of Dickie's income from his trust into your name.
他不想让...
He does not intend...
意大利人知道任何关于迪克的过去.
to give the Italians any information about Dickie's past.
他宁可希望...你也是这样想的.
He's rather hoping that...you will feel the same.
- 非常感谢,汤姆.   - 先生.
- Thank you so much, Tom. - Sir.
再见.
Good-bye.
玛吉, 我希望我那天晚上从未对你说过那些话.
Marge, I feel I never should have said those things to you the other evening.
我太慌乱了,还有戒指...你看起来又那么...
I was pretty flustered,and the rings...And you looked so...
我不知道.
I don't know.
但我希望你钱包里那张纸条能和你一回纽约...
But I hope that note goes in your purse to New York...
总有一天会用上的.
for a rainy day.
-你现在打算干吗,汤姆?   -我不知道.
- What are you gonna do now, Tom ? - I don't know.
彼得下个月在雅典有场音乐会,
Peter has a concert in Athens next month,
所以他问我是否愿意一起去帮帮他的忙.
so he asked me to come along and help out.
他向你告别.
He says good-bye.
对了,他正在预演所以不能来...
By the way, he was in rehearsal so he couldn't...
为什么我觉得瑞普雷永远都不会陷入困境?
Why do I think there's never been a Ripley rainy day ?
什么?
What ?
我知道是你干的.我知道是你干的.
I know it was you.I know it was you.
我知道是你干的!我知道是你干的!
I know it was you !I know it was you !
-玛吉,玛吉.别这样!   -我知道是你杀了迪克!
- Marge, Marge. Please ! - I know you killed Dickie !
-玛吉!   -我知道!不!
- Marge ! - I know ! No !
我知道是你干的!
[ Sobbing ]I know it was you !
玛吉.玛吉,别这样.
Marge.Marge, please.
不是汤姆.真的.
It's not Tom.Really.
我们是凤尾船船夫
[Tom And Peter]We are called gondoleri
不过那只是幻想,那是无上的光荣
But that's a vagary It's quite honorary
我们的往返旅途
The trade that we ply
问我这一刻我想改变什么.
Ask me what I want to change about this moment.
我不知道. 你想改变这一刻?
I don't know. What do you want to change about this moment ?
什么也不变.
Nothing.
我冷死了.一起下去?
[ Peter ]I'm freezing. Coming down ?
过一会. 我想看看日落.
Later. I want to catch the sunset.
-你疯了.     -我是疯了.
- You're mad. [ Chuckling ]  - I am.
迪克?
[Meredith]Dickie ?
Dickie ?
迪克!
Dickie !
[ Italian ]
哦,我的天.
Oh, my God.
你好,梅瑞迪斯.
Hello, Meredith.
我刚一直在看你.
I was looking at you.
你的衣服.我差点就认不出来了.
Your clothes.I wouldn't have known you.
呃,你发现了我,所以你拿到了你的奖励.
Well, you spotted me,so you get the reward.
-什么?   -开玩笑.
- What ? -Just kidding.
-你一个人?   -噢.
- Are you alone ?  - Oh.
难说.孤单的不能再孤单了.
Hardly.Couldn't be less alone.
-琼阿姨.  -还有叔叔
- Aunt Joan.  - And "co."
太多叔叔了
A lot of "co."
噢,天.
Oh, God.
你知道,再次看到你, 我...
You know, seeing you again, I...
在想你...
I've thought about you...
一直.
so much.
我也在想你.
And I've thought about you.
是呀,不过,当我想到你的时候,我可是很恨你的.
Yeah, well, when I've thought about you,I was mostly hating you.
你躲哪儿去了?
Where have you been hiding ?
我没躲.
I haven't been hiding.
我被警察看守.
I've been in police custody.
他们试图找出杀死弗雷迪的凶手.
They've been trying to flush out Freddie's killer.
- 你开玩笑.   - 他们给了我这个假期,
- You're kidding.  - They're giving me this vacation,
这就是我为什么打扮成这样的缘故.
which is why the getup.
这也是你为什么没听到我的消息.
Which is why you haven't heard from me.
你知道, 整个世界都认为是你杀了弗雷迪.
You know, the whole world thinks you killed Freddie.
-哦!太可怕了.   -我知道.
- Oh ! It's terrible.  - I know.
你看,我现在不能长谈.嗯,呆会见?
Listen, I can't talk now. Um, later ?
呆会见?呆会见?
Later ? Later ?
那么...
So...
[ Laughs ]
你还是以"R"为姓名首字母旅行的吗?
Are you traveling under "R" ?
你知道吗? 正是这样.
[ Laughs ]You know what ? I am.
[ Laughing ]
迪克,你是和彼得·史密斯·金斯利在一起吗?我赌你是的.
Dickie, are you with Peter Smith-Kingsley ? I bet you are.
我的姑姑说她看见他了.
My aunt thought she saw him.
彼得·史密斯·金斯利?不, 我...
Peter Smith-Kingsley ?No, I...
我已经好几个月没见过他了.
I haven't seen him in months.
不,我一个人.
No, I'm alone.
[Knocking At Door]
嗨.
Hi.
- 美吗?    - 不错.
- How was it ?  - It was good.
不过我要告诉你一些事.
But I'll tell you something.
我希望我们接下来的旅程都在这里度过.
I want us to stay in here for the rest of the trip.
[ Chuckles ]
那是梅瑞迪斯吗?
Was that Meredith ?
谁是梅瑞迪斯吗?
Was who Meredith ?
梅瑞迪斯·罗吉.你刚刚在吻什么人.看起来像是梅瑞迪斯.
Meredith Logue. You were kissing someone. It looked like Meredith.
我出去找你了.
I came out to find you.
哦,也不算是吻.
Oh, hardly kissing.
- 吻个别而已.  - 看起来不像是那样.
- Kissing off.  - It didn't look that way.
你知道吗?远远望过去?
You know ?From a distance ?
我...骗了她.
I lied... to her.
她以为她看到你了.
She thought she'd seen you.
为什么要骗她?
Why lie ?
迪克和彼得在一起.会招来太多闲言闲语.
[ Chuckling ] Dickie and Peter together. That's just too good gossip.
或是汤姆和彼得在一起.
Or Tom and Peter, even.
那甚至会招来更多闲言闲语.
That would be even better gossip.
真的吗?为什么?
Really ? Why ?
[Sighing]
我..我,嗯...我完全迷惑了.
I..I, um...[ Sighing ]I'm completely lost.
我知道.
I know.
对不起,彼得.
I'm sorry, Peter.
是我迷失了自己.
I'm lost.
我会永远被困死在地下室里了,是吗?
I'm gonna be stuck in the basement, aren't I ?
是吗?
Aren't I ?
那是我...
That's my...
可怕...
Terrible...
寂寞...
and alone...
并且黑暗的地下室.
and dark.[ Chuckles ]
我还撒了谎...
And I've lied...
关于我是谁...
about who I am...
我在哪儿.
and where I am.
现在再也没人能找到我了.
Now no one'll ever find me.[ Chuckling ]
你在说什么,撒谎说你是谁?
What do you mean,lied about who you are ?
我总是想...
I always thought it'd be better...
做一个虚假的大人物...
to be a fake somebody...
总比做个无足轻重的人好.
than a real nobody.
你到底在说什么?你怎么会是个无足轻重的人.
What are you talking about ?You're not a nobody.
你最不可能会是这种人.
That's the last thing you are.
彼得.
Peter.[Sighing]
告诉我一些关于汤姆的优点.
Tell me some good things about Tom Ripley.
别,别起来.别起来.别起来.
No, don't get up.Don't get up. Don't get up.
就...
Just...
就告诉我关于汤姆-瑞普雷的...一些优点.
Just tell me some nice things...about Tom Ripley.
[ Chuckling ]
"关于汤姆·瑞普雷的优点."
"Good things about Tom Ripley."
这可得花些时间了.
That could take me some time.
汤姆很有天赋.汤姆很温柔.
Tom is talented.Tom is tender.
汤姆很美丽.
Tom is beautiful.
你是个大骗子.
[ Crying And Chuckling ]You're such a liar.
汤姆-...汤姆是个谜.
Tom is...Tom is a mystery.
汤姆不是无足轻重.
[Peter's Voice]Tom is not a nobody.
汤姆有秘密不想告诉我,
Tom has secrets he doesn't want to tell me,
我希望他能告诉我.
and I wish he would.
汤姆会做恶梦.
Tom has nightmares.
这不是一件好事.
That’s not a good thing.
汤姆有个深爱他的人.
Tom has someone to love him.
这是件好事.
That is a good thing.
嗯.汤姆在压着我.
Mmm. [Chuckling]Tom is crushing me.
汤姆在压着我.
[Whispering]Tom is crushing me.
-汤姆.汤姆,你在压着我...
- [Tom Sobbing]- Tom. Tom, you're crush...
- 噢,上帝啊!
- [Peter Coughing, Gagging]- [Tom Sobbing] Oh, God!
Oh, God!
- 噢,上帝啊!
- [Gagging Continues]- Oh, God!
[Sobbing Continues]
- 噢,上帝啊!彼得.
Oh, God! Peter.
You don't know
What love is
Until you know the meaning of the blues
Till you love the love
You had to lose
You don't know
What love is
You don't know how lips hurt
Until you've kissed
And had to pay the cost
Until you've flipped your heart
And found you've lost
You don't know what love is
You know
Howa lost heart feels
The very thought of reminiscing
And how those lips
With a taste for tears
Soon lose their taste
For kissing
You don't know
How hearts burn
A love that cannot live
But never dies
Until you’ve reached dawn
With sleepless eyes
You don't know
What love is
And don't know
You don't know
What love is